<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Wandering Time</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://meganleewebb.github.io/</id><updated>2011-03-24T05:41:00+11:00</updated><entry><title>Finally the initial posting</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2007/06/2007-06-16-finally-the-initial-/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-06-16T09:21:00+10:00</published><updated>2007-06-16T09:21:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2007-06-16:/posts/2007/06/2007-06-16-finally-the-initial-/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well after procrastinating for long enough, I've finally created a blog for My random junk thoughts.  Not that I think I've got particularly exciting thoughts. In fact one of the reasons for not having a blog is because who cares. I mean who really cares what I think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But (isn't …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well after procrastinating for long enough, I've finally created a blog for My random junk thoughts.  Not that I think I've got particularly exciting thoughts. In fact one of the reasons for not having a blog is because who cares. I mean who really cares what I think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But (isn't there always a but) since I've just got a job working in Zurich, this is going to be a site for all my friends to check out what's happening during the moving process. Saves me having to spam everyone with email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the big Number 1 post - thats all for now:)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Where did 2008 go!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/04/2009-04-09-where-did-2008-go/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-04-09T07:48:00+10:00</published><updated>2009-04-09T07:48:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-04-09:/posts/2009/04/2009-04-09-where-did-2008-go/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, didn't end up going to Zurich. Still in Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow.. Just noticed that my last post was in 2007. Where did 2008 go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Decision Time</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/07/2009-07-21-decision-time/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-07-21T07:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2009-07-21T07:38:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-07-21:/posts/2009/07/2009-07-21-decision-time/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the weekend, it just seemed the right time. The time had come. Resignation handed in on Monday 20th July 2009.  Scarey and exciting all at the same time.  Now to wait out the time remaining. Will be interesting to see how the word goes about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things so far …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the weekend, it just seemed the right time. The time had come. Resignation handed in on Monday 20th July 2009.  Scarey and exciting all at the same time.  Now to wait out the time remaining. Will be interesting to see how the word goes about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not a fixture at the place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not a retirement home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Last Day!!!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/08/2009-08-14-last-day/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-08-14T11:56:00+10:00</published><updated>2009-08-14T11:56:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-08-14:/posts/2009/08/2009-08-14-last-day/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;14th August. Last day at work. Well, had the whole week off on leave. But was in for Wed, Thur, Friday for lunches.. Today is hand in keys and clean out the last of the desk. Exciting - its happening.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Last days</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-03-last-days/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-03T12:02:00+10:00</published><updated>2009-09-03T12:02:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-09-03:/posts/2009/09/2009-09-03-last-days/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The count down is on - though, feels very rushed.  Lots still to do and I'm so tired.. Trying to get everything to fit on the bike is needing more than a few revisions of what to take. 'Oh this shirt I've had for 20years - it must come with me'  I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The count down is on - though, feels very rushed.  Lots still to do and I'm so tired.. Trying to get everything to fit on the bike is needing more than a few revisions of what to take. 'Oh this shirt I've had for 20years - it must come with me'  I ditched the 1kg of glass that I wanted to take - decided I can find glass somewhere else...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People to see, stuff to finish up with...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Leaving Sydney for Morriset</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-12-leaving-sydney-for-m/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-12T06:01:00+10:00</published><updated>2009-09-12T06:01:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-09-12:/posts/2009/09/2009-09-12-leaving-sydney-for-m/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LoadedUp.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LoadedUp.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left Sydney Saturday 5th September for Morriset. Was sad saying farewell to friends over the past few weeks, and my home for the past year. Was exciting also to be finally on my way. I had lots piled on the bike. Panniers full to busting, a bag tied on top …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LoadedUp.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LoadedUp.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left Sydney Saturday 5th September for Morriset. Was sad saying farewell to friends over the past few weeks, and my home for the past year. Was exciting also to be finally on my way. I had lots piled on the bike. Panniers full to busting, a bag tied on top and stuff hanging off everywhere...  (Anna and Serena got up early just to see me off.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LoadedUp2.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LoadedUp2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/SerenaAnna.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/SerenaAnna.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much stuff on the bike,  that first stop at Claires place we went though it all and I left another box of stuff behind - mainly clothes, and the yoga mat, thongs, etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/claire.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/claire.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LighterLoad.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/LighterLoad.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That reduced the weight a bit.. But by the time I got to Morriset, decided to ditch some more things. I think that managed to lose 6kg of stuff here. Decided that I didn't really need to take that extra shifting spanner (on a bike with mostly allen keys), multigrips (why??), and file (what was I thinking???).. or need so much food..(months and months supply!!!)  a container of grease (on a bike with all sealed bearings!!!), half the bookcase (maps of all of Australia - what was I thinking!!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twin boys here are so cute. But so much work. Always busy.. been taking naps in the day when they sleep to recover. They just turn two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingo and Andrea have been so wonderful. Love Andreas cooking!. But after sorting out more stuff on the bike, time to hit the road again.. Leave Sunday for the nearest National Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/twins.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2009/twins.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Tamworth</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-21-tamworth/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-21T12:19:00+10:00</published><updated>2009-09-21T12:19:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-09-21:/posts/2009/09/2009-09-21-tamworth/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yeah.. bit of a story. After spending 5 days camping in Watagans National Park. (I had a good time there.. no one else was at the camp sites - guess they are all working) I moved to Wolombi Pub for one night, then went to Broke. Camping in both places. Broke …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yeah.. bit of a story. After spending 5 days camping in Watagans National Park. (I had a good time there.. no one else was at the camp sites - guess they are all working) I moved to Wolombi Pub for one night, then went to Broke. Camping in both places. Broke was a nice camp site, but got too noise - with someone wanting to keep me company so I would be lonely. They also brought their juke box along. So next day was heading to Denman very early in the morning. A rent a van stopped, and a guy lept out and said to chuck the bike in the back and he'd give me a lift. Well I said no. But we got talking, he's an artist and was heading to Tamworth to collect his paintings from the exhibition that he'd been displayed at. Obviously here I am - been helping him pack up his paintings. Ian Bettinson is his name, and the paintings were worth it. Amazing dot paintings. Glad I accepted the lift. Been here a couple of days, leaving tomorrow. Going to cycle backwards towards Sydney to see some of the national parks I skipped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should also add that I've been dumping stuff every stop. Getting less and less. Pushing the bike up the hills, you think carefully about what you need. Will get another shot of the bike soon. I can say that there is now space in the panniers :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Nundle</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/09/2009-09-28-nundle/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-28T12:52:00+10:00</published><updated>2009-09-28T12:52:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-09-28:/posts/2009/09/2009-09-28-nundle/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well packing up an exhibition was interesting. The paintings were 'wow'. Doing the work, was thinking of how to make it easier. It took all day. Also got to been some of Ians friends in Tamworth - Hi to Col, Kate and Molly (How could you forget Molly!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cycled out …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well packing up an exhibition was interesting. The paintings were 'wow'. Doing the work, was thinking of how to make it easier. It took all day. Also got to been some of Ians friends in Tamworth - Hi to Col, Kate and Molly (How could you forget Molly!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cycled out of Tamworth on Tuesday morning, and got to Woolomin. The rain started there, so camped in the camp ground. Well next day was the dust storm - so wasn't going anywhere. The local shop has books that you can take and read - so spent the past week sheltering from the wind and dust, reading books. Been taking the tent down in the day - and sheltering underneath it to cut the wind down. Oh I'd like the wind to stop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning was 1 Degree. With the wind, its cold. I'm going to wait about for another couple of days for this cold front to pass, and the weather to warm up. There is a forecast for 30C on Wednesday or Thursday. Just heard that its 8C now, and that doesn't count the wind!!! Not sure about Barrington Tops either at the moment. Everyone is saying its always cold there. I don't think my clothes are up for the cold. The question I'm still thinking is wether to sit here in Nundle, or go back down to Woolomin where its a bit warmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still not so good with taking pictures. So no pictures yet. Still getting rid of stuff on the bike, though, the items are small now -&amp;gt; do I need this cloth? Still would like it to be lighter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been talking to lots of locals and tourists (as you do shivering in a campsite). By far the most common exclaimation is 'your mad' followed by 'get more gears'. But some people think its a good idea (even if they wouldn't do it themself)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meals have settled down to once a day - doing a large rice/pasta/vege dish about lunch time, with any desserts if there are any. Eat any fruit when I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ever I do, I'll be heading in Walcha eventually and will get another update up then.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Nundle, Woolomin, Tamworth, Manila</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/10/2009-10-13-nundle-woolomin-tamw/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-10-13T09:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2009-10-13T09:00:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-10-13:/posts/2009/10/2009-10-13-nundle-woolomin-tamw/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the quick update at Nundle, I headed up to Hanging Rock. The plan was to head to Barrington Tops. However, it was cold!! It was midday when I got up there, had lunch at a place called Shiba Dam (Had a picnic at Hanging Rock), and I was shivering …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the quick update at Nundle, I headed up to Hanging Rock. The plan was to head to Barrington Tops. However, it was cold!! It was midday when I got up there, had lunch at a place called Shiba Dam (Had a picnic at Hanging Rock), and I was shivering. If it was that cold at midday, I thought the nights might be too cold for me, so I headed back to Woolomin. Took me 1.5 hours to walk up to Hanging Rock, and 5 minutes to coast down. I did camp one night at Nundle, and found ice on the tent in the morning when I woke. Woolomin was cold, but not as cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the last three weeks, there has been lots of shivering! Still getting rid of stuff - down to just a pair of sandals now - got rid of the shoes I had. I've never liked shoes that much, so not sure why I thought I would suddenly start wearing them now. Gone. 1.5kg lighter (they were heavy shoes!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing about Woolomin was that Merv and George had all these books. The General Store had books also, so I did a lot of reading while I was there. George went ferreting on the last weekend, and brought me a rabbit skin. I wanted to try brain tanning it. Well, I learnt alot about hides - fleshing the hide wasn't as easy as I thought it would be. After several hours, cramps in my hands, holes in the pelt, I admitted defeat. I know for next time - start with a more comfortable handled knife, a hard surface to work on, have water handy, and probably start on not such an old rabbit. The pelt was from and old female and was very mangy. But still for a first try, I was happy. No I didn't get to the tanning stage. Next time. Though then I'll have to catch the rabbit myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For interested people, here is the link on how I was going to do the tanning: http://www.braintan.com/articles/furs/miller1.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Tamworth yesterday, but had internet problems so didn't get an update.  I'm now at the Manila caravan park. And it is a nice park. My lesson from yesterday is 'drink water'. I set out from Woolomin about 8, got to Tamwoth at 9:30, did postal stuff, internet, some shopping, and then set out. About lunch time cramps started, and I struggled on to Manilia before thinking about why. Realised that I'd only drunk about a liter all day, and the day was very dry. Also had a head wind the whole way. (Why is it that when I stop the wind goes the way I want to head, but the moment I start riding I get a head wind?) Decided that I'll rest up here for a couple of days to recover before moving on.  There are also more books here to read :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry to all the people that I've got email addresses for that I've not emailed yet. I keep forgetting and packing the address book at the bottom of the bags. Sooner or later I'll rememeber and keep it on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the first day not shivering, and now the weather here has gone cold :( Hope the washing dries - my jumper is in it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Manilla, Barraba</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/10/2009-10-23-manilla-barraba/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-10-23T10:56:00+11:00</published><updated>2009-10-23T10:56:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-10-23:/posts/2009/10/2009-10-23-manilla-barraba/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Decided that needed to move on from Manilla. Was a nice town, but itchy feet. The day was windy and dusty, so thought I might as well be walking northwards. It was very windy and dusty on the road. Almost headed back to Manilla. Had decided that I'd only stop …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Decided that needed to move on from Manilla. Was a nice town, but itchy feet. The day was windy and dusty, so thought I might as well be walking northwards. It was very windy and dusty on the road. Almost headed back to Manilla. Had decided that I'd only stop in Barraba for water, but when I got here, thought I'd stay the night. One night led to two, to three... Been here more than a week so far.. Going to stay a few more too. There is the Barraba Festival on in the first weekend in November - so will probably stay for that. I'm staying at the Barraba Caravan Park. (Hi Bob.) Its quiet and peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exciting things that have happened - I cut my hair! This is the first time in I don't remember how many years. So it was a good cut. I used scissors first - but the cut was uneven. Then in a second had shop I found some hand clippers for only $10. Bargin. I was so excited. Today, for the first time all week, my hair is even. Number 000 clippers - pretty close to a shave without using a razor. Not sure yet if I'll just stick to the clippers, or actually do the shaving. Time will tell. It certainly is a change from my long hair. Dries quick though, and is easier to wash. Also saves on shampoo and conditioner :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days are passing watching the insect life (there are lots of ants about here - all different sizes, shapes), playing with the Roly Poly's (
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armadillidiidae"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armadillidiidae&lt;/a&gt;
they are soo neat!!) , watching clouds, and reading. I also go for rides about the town and local roads when it is cool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Barraba</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/10/2009-10-30-barraba/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-10-30T11:14:00+11:00</published><updated>2009-10-30T11:14:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-10-30:/posts/2009/10/2009-10-30-barraba/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The weekend had lots of steady rain and the tent leaked :( First one side above the door started with slow drops falling, then the other door, then another leak further back into the tent. The drips were from the seems over the top of the tent. I thought it was …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The weekend had lots of steady rain and the tent leaked :( First one side above the door started with slow drops falling, then the other door, then another leak further back into the tent. The drips were from the seems over the top of the tent. I thought it was leaking when I was in Woolomin, but as I had the vents open, wasn't certain if the water was from that or not. Another possibility at the time was from my raincoat - I had been in and out a few times. Decided not to worry about it then, and wait until we had more rain to check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well the weekends rain made it clear that it was leaking.  I have an Exped, 2 person,  Auriga Mesh tent. Well had. Called Mountain Equipment in Sydney, and talked with Heather. the tent is 6 months old. Considering that I've only been using it the last 6 weeks - that's not much use yet. Heather said they have never had problems with these tents, so she thinks this may be faulty. I posted the rain fly back to Sydney yesterday.  Exped has a 5 year warrenty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the mean time, I have a 3 person tent from Barbeques Galore. It cost me the pricely sum of $49. I also bought a green poly tarp from Bunnings just in case. The 3 person is more roomy, not as ventilated, but so far, has kept the rain off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tarp is also for covering the tent when the sun is out - if I'm not moving. Tents don't like the sun - and all of them have warnings about prolonged UV exposure. So if I'm in a spot that is very sunny and am not moving for a while, then I'll cover the tent with the tarp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment I'll stay in Barraba a bit longer, but thinking its getting time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Return to Sydney</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/11/2009-11-10-return-to-sydney/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-10T08:02:00+11:00</published><updated>2009-11-10T08:02:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-11-10:/posts/2009/11/2009-11-10-return-to-sydney/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yep, you read that right. Back in Sydney now.  The short story is that I've cannot carry enough water by bicycle to do the things I want - travel to remote places. The places I've been are dry. The more water I carry, the heavier it is, and the more I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yep, you read that right. Back in Sydney now.  The short story is that I've cannot carry enough water by bicycle to do the things I want - travel to remote places. The places I've been are dry. The more water I carry, the heavier it is, and the more I drink pushing it up hills. End result, I cannot get to places I want. My knee has also been a bit sore, my tent is in Sydney getting repaired.  When I bought a motorcycle, the bicycle would return to Sydney anyway... And so, seemed the time to return to look about Sydney shops, see a doc, recover tent, etc..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Sunday I left Barraba and travelled to Manilla. Monday morning I left Manilla at 6am to get to Tamworth in time for the CountryLink train to Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to find a motorcycle.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Motorcycle!!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2009/12/2009-12-10-motorcycle/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-12-10T15:08:00+11:00</published><updated>2009-12-10T15:08:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2009-12-10:/posts/2009/12/2009-12-10-motorcycle/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bought a Yamaha Scorpio-Z 225cc road bike. Had a test ride on the Yamaha TTR-250 - but I've a shortage of height... Found stopping scary - not being able to touch the ground except on tippy toes. The Yamaha XT250 looked nice... but no kick start.. I decided that I didn't want …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bought a Yamaha Scorpio-Z 225cc road bike. Had a test ride on the Yamaha TTR-250 - but I've a shortage of height... Found stopping scary - not being able to touch the ground except on tippy toes. The Yamaha XT250 looked nice... but no kick start.. I decided that I didn't want to have to push start my bike if the battery was feeling slack. Used to do that in the past. It was hard work on bitumen, I reckon it would be a lot harder on dirt or sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Scorpio was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have build a rack to go on it - version 2 is much nicer than version 1. Version 1 weighed 10kg  and wasn't finished - that is when I thought it was way way over engineered, and scrapped it..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to head out of Sydney for a week to test how it all goes. Will have photos up from that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2009-12-29 06:22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Nasher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Megan,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lana and I are following your adventurous journey. It seems scary sometimes, but glad to hear that you are safe. I think getting a motorcycle is a great idea. You'll have a lot more freedom to actually get to places and do things you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have moved into our new house and have plenty of room for you to come visit when you're done travelling in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take care,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nash&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Far North Queensland</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/02/2010-02-02-far-north-queensland/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-02T14:28:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-02-02T14:28:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-02-02:/posts/2010/02/2010-02-02-far-north-queensland/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay am way behind on the blog. So this is going to be a quick catchup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week trip went well enough. The ride went from Sydney north. Stayed with friends in Morriset for a few days. Then camped in the Watagans back to the first camp site. I made …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Okay am way behind on the blog. So this is going to be a quick catchup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week trip went well enough. The ride went from Sydney north. Stayed with friends in Morriset for a few days. Then camped in the Watagans back to the first camp site. I made the mistake of riding in in the rain. When the guide says 'slippery when wet' they really mean it. The road that was hard dirt when I bicycled, turned to slippery clay in the rain. It was a dreadful time riding the motorcycle in. If the first bit hadn't been uphill, and I hadn't been worried about dropping the bike, I'd had turned around half way up the hill and left. By the top of the hill, the prospect of trying to ride down it was also scary enough that I pushed on. I was sorry with that decision more than once before hitting the campground. Luckily by the time I left two days later, it had stopped raining and the road was hard again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Watagans, I went to Barrington Tops and camped near the river. Great swimming spot if you were inclined. Unfortunately the stay was spoilt  by the amount of rubbish and crap about. The toilets near by had been demolished to build a new block, but there where other toilets further away. A lot of people hadn't used these. The bush between the campsite and the river was disgusting. Burying waste doesn't seem to happen. Walking past turds to get to the water, spoilt the idea of swimming for me. Talking to some other campers nearby, they didn't have a problem with swimming or drinking the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrington Tops to Broke. But didn't like the feel of Broke this time, so moved on and camped elsewhere. An advantage of the motorcycle - can easily move no matter how late in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the riding was okay, if I stayed going slow. Riding on the freeway was boring as.  So monotonous. Everyone goes fast there. I thought trucks were speed limited to 100km/hr? These seems to not be the case. Learners limited to 80km/hr - doesn't seem the case either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stayed in Sydney for the Xmass/New Year period. After this I set off to Canberra. My planned leisurely trip was cut short by the realisation that unless I hit the freeway, I wouldn't get there until late at night. Since my uncle and aunty were expecting me for tea, I took the freeway.  With rest stops and hills, I got to Canberra in time for tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After catching up with family for a couple of days I set off North. I camped places I new - so end up staying in Barraba again. Went to see some of the sites that I hadn't seen when I was there previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Barraba to the Gold Coast was a 9.5 hour ride. I did stop over in Texas!!  Let me say that soon as I crossed the border into Queensland, it day seemed brighter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last bit of road close to the Gold Coast was uneasy. The traffic had picked up. The roads where single lane, and no one drives to the speed limit. It didn't matter if the zone was a 40, 60, 80 or 100 km/hr.  I had thought my speedo was inaccurate - but no. People speed. Worse than speeding for me was the unsafe overtaking that occurred. Drivers have been watching too many tv commercials and believe that their car/truck can overtake anything instantly. It didn't matter blind curves, oncoming traffic - drivers would overtake. There were several times when I had to slow down to let the over taking complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After staying with friends on the Gold Coast, I set the GPS for Cairns and set off. I'm so glad for the GPS. I'm not sure where I went, I just followed the roads - well as near as was practicable. I haven't updated the maps, so some streets had changed, but drive on and  "recalculating"  soon sorted it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a long day I stopped outside Rockhampton. I sign that I wasn't thinking well - I booked into a van park near the road. Not only near the road, but near a train line also. Both kept up throughout the night. Even with ear plugs in, you could still hear them. The vibrations did provide a sort of massage through the ground. And the mossies!!! I don't think I'd set the tent up so fast and jumped in. Hordes of mossies. I've never seen so many mossies. They where like fur on the outside of the tent wanting to get in. I didn't leave the tent all night. Next morning I fully dressed in motorcycle gear - including helmet and gloves before exiting and packing up. A fast packup even with all that. I was glad to be moving again and be out of the mossies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was another long day - and I reached my grandmothers house about 7:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The doors where already closed, and after knocking and banging. I called her on the phone. We then had 10 minutes of comedy before I convinced her that I really was outside. I was looking forward to a shower. Unfortunately grandma closed the door again from habit. This time the phone was inside. I did eventually get inside - it just took a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I'm about 120km south of Cairns. Visiting my folks.  The nearest town is Moresby, the nearest major town is Innisfail. Check them out in Google. Its been raining since I got here, but today the sun is out and the humidity is back. I sweat sitting still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride from the Gold Coast to here, was a nightmare. I never want to to that again. Ever. When I was younger I had motorcycles, and did long rides. I remember the hard part was the sitting - cramped muscles, insect stings - I rode without gloves, and with an open face helmet. This trip the other motorist where the worry. Traffic has grown more heavy since I last rode a motorcycle. Trucks have gotten bigger. Super sized!  Even on the motorcycle, these things whip up the wind when they pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on dual lane roads, it was okay. Everyone overtook in the other lane. On single lane roads -&amp;gt; I lost track of the number of times slowing down to let drivers finish overtaking. Drivers over took on double lines, corners, turn lanes, on the left on a single lane road!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone speeds. The only vehicle I overtook on the way up was a tractor - doing 30 in a 60 zone. Everyone else overtook me. Didn't matter if I was sitting on the speed limit in the zone - I was overtaken. And the car/truck then vanished into the distance.  If I moved a bit too left to avoid a patch on the road - someone would try to overtake. I ended up on the road shoulder several times - forced there by people overtaking.  Once I ended up on the shoulder when a truck overtook, and as it passed, I saw that a car was overtaking it at the same time! Following too closely - trucks, cars or buses - it didn't matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I miss a rule that says that the speed limit is the minimum and there is some speed over that that you must do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police? Yeah, getting a speeding ticket is "Bad Luck". There are so few police on the roads, that it really is a case of bad luck if your busted for speeding, following too closely, or any other traffic offense. I saw two cop cars/speed checks the whole way up. They were evident by the flashing lights of people coming towards me and the general slow down of speeds until they'd been passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was glad to get to the end of the trip up here. If people were overtaking me like that, then what is coming around the next corner? "Accidents" shouldn't be called accidents. They are crashes, and the surprising thing is that there are so few of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been here for two weeks now, and the dodge'em car road driving conditions continues. If you've ever had a car sitting on your tail light and your doing 100km/hr in a 100km/hr zone, you might know the worry of it. The only advantage to being in an 80km/hr or 60km/hr  zone is that the speed is slower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be honest to say I'm not enjoying riding the motorcycle on the roads with other traffic. I'm also suffering from a bad case of  bicycle withdrawals. Going to have to do something about.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Bicycle, Bicycle, I want to ride my Bicycle!!!!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/02/2010-02-14-bicycle-bicycle-i-wa/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-02-14T12:48:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-02-14T12:48:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-02-14:/posts/2010/02/2010-02-14-bicycle-bicycle-i-wa/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bicycle absence symptoms became too much. After brooding about it for a few weeks, and riding the motorcycle about - I'm getting my bicycle back.  Well, soonish.  I now rate the motorcycle as one of the silliest decisions I've made. Missing bicycling too much. So, if I'm not able to get …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bicycle absence symptoms became too much. After brooding about it for a few weeks, and riding the motorcycle about - I'm getting my bicycle back.  Well, soonish.  I now rate the motorcycle as one of the silliest decisions I've made. Missing bicycling too much. So, if I'm not able to get to every part of Australia that I'd like to because of riding a bicycle, then so be it. That still leaves a heck of a lot of country to see. And in the end, I'd rather be bicycling and miss seeing things, than not cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've very very lucky that my friend Claire convinced me to leave my bicycle at her place, rather than sell it. So lucky!  Before my bicycle comes back, it is going to get an small upgrade. Yeah, going for some gears this time around. The guys at
Cheeky Transport &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org"&gt;Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt; for http://www.cheekytransport.com.au&lt;/sup&gt;
(Adam,Dave,Nic,Lee) are going to sort that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I miss about the bicycle? Heres a list in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pedaling, the sense of achievement when you arrive at your destination, the slower speed, being involved with your surroundings,  picking up useful things (some people call this junk!!!) from the side of the road, spotting the things on the side of the road, seeing everything, the sounds of the countryside, feeling the cool air in the hollows, the gentle breezes, feel of rain falling, being warm when its wet, exercise, being able to eat all you want, not having to stop at service stations (once upon a time, you might have gotten service, now all you do is pay for the lack of service, and the petrol), not using petrol (I don' t know about you, but the smell of petrol isn't on my "nice" smells list), doing the best with where you are, the sound of your cleats clicking in, wind on your face, ease of jump on and off, being able to lift it over a fence,  the silence, not having to wear earplugs, being able to eat all you want, whirring of the free wheel, remembering the journey (you remember the hills that you struggle up, the corner when you were tired,  the view when you top a hill), downhill thrills, the tired feeling after a days cycling, hearing the birds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well you get the idea.. Lots of good things..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss my bike. Hope it forgives me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Bicycle Bicycle - I want to ride my bicycle</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/03/2010-03-18-bicycle-bicycle-i-wa/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-03-18T14:55:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-03-18T14:55:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-03-18:/posts/2010/03/2010-03-18-bicycle-bicycle-i-wa/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;YES!!! I've my bicycle back :) Soo happy..  My bike has forgiven me. Well, it is extracting some revenge. Breathing is laboured and my bum is tender - but this will pass. The joy of riding again will not though. So much better than on the motorcycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so lucky that Claire …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;YES!!! I've my bicycle back :) Soo happy..  My bike has forgiven me. Well, it is extracting some revenge. Breathing is laboured and my bum is tender - but this will pass. The joy of riding again will not though. So much better than on the motorcycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm so lucky that Claire kept my bike for me. Thanks also to Claire for giving me back a rack to be able to leave Sydney now. I ordered another Tubus Cosmo, but it has not arrived yet. So I've the old one off Claire, and she will get the new one when it arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trip to Sydney was a rush decision. Needed a break from my family, and wanted to get my bicycle. Had some other stuff to sort out, that I could have in a pinch have sorted without being in Sydney, but that just gave me an excuse to come down and get my bicycle, rather than wait for it to post up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not been able to catch up with all the people I wanted to. Kind of hard to fit it in with friends working. So, sorry to everyone I didn't get to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading out of Sydney tomorrow morning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Central station</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/03/2010-03-19-central-station/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-03-19T09:46:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-03-19T09:46:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-03-19:/posts/2010/03/2010-03-19-central-station/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-03-19-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-03-19-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving Sydney yet again. This stop over was much shorter - less than a week.If you compare the bike photo from this time to the last time, it obviously has been on a diet. (Unlike me) This will be third time lucky. Will be trying to update the web site …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-03-19-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-03-19-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving Sydney yet again. This stop over was much shorter - less than a week.If you compare the bike photo from this time to the last time, it obviously has been on a diet. (Unlike me) This will be third time lucky. Will be trying to update the web site more, using a mobile phone from my brother. Its a Nokia 6120 Classic. Lets see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Day one over</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/03/2010-03-25-day-one-over/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-03-25T08:05:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-03-25T08:05:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-03-25:/posts/2010/03/2010-03-25-day-one-over/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24032010-724083.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24032010-724083.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long day. 90 km.Tired me out.Wonderful riding again.Hearing the birds,the wind in the trees.I rode with butterflies.Glad i've the bike back.Gears make it heaps better than the single speed.And i needed all the gears!I need to lose weight though-me as well …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24032010-724083.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24032010-724083.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long day. 90 km.Tired me out.Wonderful riding again.Hearing the birds,the wind in the trees.I rode with butterflies.Glad i've the bike back.Gears make it heaps better than the single speed.And i needed all the gears!I need to lose weight though-me as well as the gear i have.At the moment all the shift has been to my stomach and the to the waist. A longer update when i get to an internet cafe. On to Denman'ish area today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>A big hill</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/03/2010-03-28-a-big-hill/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-03-28T16:51:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-03-28T16:51:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-03-28:/posts/2010/03/2010-03-28-a-big-hill/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28032010-798768.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28032010-798768.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long days. Just felt like riding. Tired out alot though. Reckon i'm getting thinner. Will have a rest for easter though. Should be in Barraba then.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Barraba!!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-01-barraba/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-01T11:05:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-04-01T11:05:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-01:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-01-barraba/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Total Distance: 548km&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrived yesterday afternoon! Was good to see the silos as you come into town again. Means that I get to rest for a few days while this pesty Easter business gets over with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can give a better summay of what has been happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 1 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Total Distance: 548km&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrived yesterday afternoon! Was good to see the silos as you come into town again. Means that I get to rest for a few days while this pesty Easter business gets over with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can give a better summay of what has been happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ride from Morriset to Wollombi was hard. It was hot, and the ride seemed to be always uphill. I did a detour in the Watagans to visit my old camp site. Yep it was still there.. This 20km detour I was to regret as the day went on.  My days of sitting about had reduced my fitness and expanded my waitline. I wheezed and huffed and puffed along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it was good to be back on the bike. Only saw a couple of cars all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wollombi to Broke.  Was feeling so tired this day. Riding slow. Sore legs. By the time I got to Broke I just wanted to rest. So I did. Met up with Dennis again. Lucky this time he was not all doom and gloom about my travels. I had a bit of the flu - nose runnign, sore throat. So ate oranges and rested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broke to Denman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felt stronger and got to Jerry Plains just on 12. But then it started getting really hot. In the next three hours, only went 2km. Lots of resting in the shade of trees. Even at 4pm the sun was still burning. I was a bit worried about being lost - as I'd taken a side ride. And well, a very rough map, and my sense of direction, I was hoping that it would go to Denman in the end.. It did.  Hung out in the park and drank lots of water. Road out of town as the sun set and camped by the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denman, Musselbrook, Scone. Hung out in the park for a while then rode out to the Washingpools Camp area. This is in a National Park - so you have to pay to camp there. I'd been told it was free. Had a good swim, and a wash, set up camp, and started to sleep. But then all these cars started to arrive, kids with alcohol, loud voices, and a duf duf box. I packed up about 9pm and left. Cars where still arriving. Music thumping. I pity the poor people I left behind that where hoping for a quiet night. Riding in the dark by moon light (and my lights) was good.. It was quiet, cool, peaceful. Even on the highway, you got lots of warning of cars/trucks comming. Ended up stopping Widgen. There was a horse event the Saturday/Sunday - so lots of people (and horses).  Could have had a hot shower here also if I'd waited long enough.. But I didn't - figured that I'd be hot and sweaty before to long so why bother...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Widgen to Wallabadah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Car drivers know nothing about hills. Been hearing about the Murrurundi Hills. But it turned out that it was easy as. 30 minutes climb and then a long downhill. Easy...  See the last post of "A big Hill'.. The harder part was the long climb out of Willow Tree to Wallabadah. The climb seems to go on and on... It was also very hot that day, so that didn't help.  But like all things - it passes and Wallabadah was a great spot to stay the night. I had planned on being in Woolomin, but was too tired to go on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had the first puncture today in Murrurundi. Wasn't watching and rode over a tent peg on the road. Clang, crash, clang, it rattled about with the wheel until pissssss.. Then it fell off. This was right outside a servo, with a broken air pump.. Least it was shady patching it..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got the great comment then from on the the drivers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Gee you got a lot of stuff"   What could I do but laugh.. He was walking to his 4x4 packed to the roof with stuff,  the roof rack heaped, and towing a caravan..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabadah to Woolomin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another not so flat rode. Went over some "Gap" Was moving too fast to read the name.. But it was a lot of uphill then a long downhill. Got 68Km/hr on the downhill - a new speed record for this trip. Serious downhill. Woolomin was nice - stocked up with heaps of books from the General Store, and ate lots of their hot chips - had a real craving for them, so had three lots. Best chips I've tasted. Talked with a few of the people from the last trip there..Rested, slept...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woolomin to Attunga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice ride. Stopped and talked to Terry on the side of the road. He has a drinking water business. Rode into Tamworth and meet up with Claire and Wayne
&lt;a href="http://www.cwbikingoz.com/"&gt;http://www.cwbikingoz.com/&lt;/a&gt;
as soon as I stopped. Found Tamworth too busy feeling, so after a quick stop for a screw for my sandals, some food, I kept cycling to Attunga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Barry and Margaret of Attunga who let me stay in their back yard, feed me, and gave me a hot shower. My first since leaving Morriset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 8 Attunga to Barraba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A slow day, seemed be a lot of gentle uphills. Apart from a stop at the Manilla cake shop (yum!!!) nothing much to say. Arrived in Barraba and met up with people I knew. Lots were surprised to see me back so soon. A nice place to hang out for easter when all the busy people are on the roads..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washing day!!! Had been washing my clothes when I could. I didn't think they smelled, but had a lot of salt in them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>My tent</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-01-my-tent/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-01T18:47:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-04-01T18:47:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-01:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-01-my-tent/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/01042010-754256.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/01042010-754256.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo will not capture a fraction of the light that the setting sun shows about my tent. The day ends beautifully. The air is cool (finally), my belly is full, Pachelbel on piano is playing. Its been a restful day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Restless</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-04-restless/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-04T15:39:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-04T15:39:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-04:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-04-restless/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04042010-798049.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04042010-798049.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished reading my books.filled my belly and had a rest.Hot shower was nice also.But was restless, so today moved to Bingara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was easy 60km ride. Got new max speed of 73.78km/hr.But there didn't seem to be much of an up hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check my camp …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04042010-798049.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04042010-798049.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished reading my books.filled my belly and had a rest.Hot shower was nice also.But was restless, so today moved to Bingara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was easy 60km ride. Got new max speed of 73.78km/hr.But there didn't seem to be much of an up hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check my camp site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the Sims and the Bailey's for a yummy hot x bun, sandwich, easter eggs and ginger beer.thanks to another couple for home made biscuits. Very spoilt I am today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>North Star</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-06-north-star/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-06T10:18:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-06T10:18:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-06:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-06-north-star/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well the might sleep was not good. Too many dogs barking all night.Used earplugs.The next day was feeling like pedalling. At 110km the feeling passed.But still another 15 go.Was tired that night. Now i'm in Queensland:) at Goodiwindi. Will go further today, but not as far …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well the might sleep was not good. Too many dogs barking all night.Used earplugs.The next day was feeling like pedalling. At 110km the feeling passed.But still another 15 go.Was tired that night. Now i'm in Queensland:) at Goodiwindi. Will go further today, but not as far as yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Condamine</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-08-condamine/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-08T12:52:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-08T12:52:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-08:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-08-condamine/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/08042010-742948.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/08042010-742948.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-04-08-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-04-08-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well the last few days have been pedal, pedal, pedal. Into a headwind the whole time. Been doing 100km days.Long and slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See if you can spot the difference on the from and to photos. Big empty spaces. The headwinds keep the flies down though.But watch out at …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/08042010-742948.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/08042010-742948.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-04-08-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-04-08-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well the last few days have been pedal, pedal, pedal. Into a headwind the whole time. Been doing 100km days.Long and slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See if you can spot the difference on the from and to photos. Big empty spaces. The headwinds keep the flies down though.But watch out at night, the mozzies are bad. I sleep to there buzzing - outside the tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been camping by the road, but today a combo of tired and needing a wash, have had a short day. To celebrate 1000km tomorrow, i've my first shower in Qld. The clothes got washed also.:)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Theodore</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-12-theodore/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-12T07:22:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-12T07:22:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-12:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-12-theodore/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/09042010-786061.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/09042010-786061.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have i seen this range before?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resting in Theodore now. Days and nights have been baking hot and humid. Rode during the night to avoid the sun, but it was still hot. Where's the cool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have started using Areogard as had so many mossie bites i looked like a plague …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/09042010-786061.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/09042010-786061.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have i seen this range before?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resting in Theodore now. Days and nights have been baking hot and humid. Rode during the night to avoid the sun, but it was still hot. Where's the cool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have started using Areogard as had so many mossie bites i looked like a plague victim. Now i bath several times a day in the repellent. Is this the same as washing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My clothes and me have not been dry for days.Constant wet cloths, the humidity, get smelly fast.With mossie bites, wet clothes, and i'm looking thinner i get lots of personal space at rest stops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can eat 2 minute noodles with out cooking. They are yummy!Even the flavour packets are good-but some are hot and spicy.Save them for the baked beans.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Another restful day</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-13-another-restful-day/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-13T16:27:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-13T16:27:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-13:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-13-another-restful-day/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It showered today. Its cooler. And hopefully this cool weather will continue. Tomorrow is an easy 60km to Banana. Reckon it will have a giant banana?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ate up well today again. My chickpeas sprouted. More yoghurt. Corn. And some biscuits.:)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Yaamba</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-15-yaamba/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-15T14:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-15T14:40:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-15:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-15-yaamba/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well Banana had only two servo's, and a post office. No big or little bananas.Since i'd arrived early (8am), haven riden since 4.30am i decided not to stay and headed to Wowan. It wasn't that nice a place when i arrived. And the only person i saw wasn't …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well Banana had only two servo's, and a post office. No big or little bananas.Since i'd arrived early (8am), haven riden since 4.30am i decided not to stay and headed to Wowan. It wasn't that nice a place when i arrived. And the only person i saw wasn't that nice, so i headed to Dululu. And there i stayed as that was 140km for the day. I was tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning i left early. It was a no moon night. The milky way was visible. Oh so beautiful! I twisted my neck a bit looking up and around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just before Westwood the Leichhardt highway came to an end. I'd riden the whole length of it. I was sorry it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockhampton- not nice. The drivers are bad. Heaps of traffic.Noisy. I'm missing the country roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopping in Yaamba today at 120km. Enough for today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>St Lawrence</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-17-st-lawrence/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-17T16:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-17T16:30:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-17:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-17-st-lawrence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yaamba turned out to be nice roadside stop. The pub had a good feed on also. I couldn't bring myself to stop in Rockhampton. The only shops i saw was in Stocklands shopping complex. Think of a brick with doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had planned on stopping at Marlborough and did initially …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yaamba turned out to be nice roadside stop. The pub had a good feed on also. I couldn't bring myself to stop in Rockhampton. The only shops i saw was in Stocklands shopping complex. Think of a brick with doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had planned on stopping at Marlborough and did initially. But the town so annoyed me i left. Had to pay for water there. The pub or the shop would not give me any.It takes my worst town award. 151km to St Lawrence it was. I arrived at 6pm.A much nicer place. Been resting today. Might move on tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Rest, Recover and Repair.</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/04/2010-04-25-rest-recover-and-rep/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-25T07:18:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-04-25T07:18:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-04-25:/posts/2010/04/2010-04-25-rest-recover-and-rep/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I arrived at my parents place at 10am on Friday 23rd.  So now for a big update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dululu to Yaamba - the riding in the night was awesome!! It was a no moon night, and out of the streetlights there is so much of the night sky to see. I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I arrived at my parents place at 10am on Friday 23rd.  So now for a big update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dululu to Yaamba - the riding in the night was awesome!! It was a no moon night, and out of the streetlights there is so much of the night sky to see. I annoyed my neck with twisting around so much while riding to look at the milky way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yaamba to St Lawrence;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marlborough. I meet another cyclist outside of Bowen -&amp;gt; Colin. Talking with him about camping at Marlborough Hotel - he had a much better experience than me.  He also got water off them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St Lawrence - Thanks to the couple that gave me the tin of baked beans and some bread. That was dinner when I arrived.  Another couple gave me some fruit and veges from a food hamper that they had won earlier up the coast. They didn't have a fridge and couldn't eat all the food. It was much appreciated. Food prices at St Lawrence shops where much more reasonable - so I bought other food there. Actually, when I left the I had much too much food in my pannier. But this was soon fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St Lawrence to Sarina; Well the day was to have stopped at Ilbilbi.  But when I arrived it was blowing a wind - a  wonderful tailwind.. What can you do - you keep going.  It was showering by this time also, with heavy rain just outside of Sarina.  The ladies at the Sarina Information Center were very helpful - and found a caravan park 10km further North that only wanted $10 for an unpowered site.  It also had the advantage of being opposite a fruit and vege shop and was out of town.  It was a good spot. I ate  a bag of mandarins and bananas for dinner :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarina to Proserpine:  Well actually I camped about 30km from Proserpine. More tail winds and showers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proserpine to Guthalungra: More tail winds. This was when I caught up with Colin. We rode from Bowen to Guthalungra.  Colin had started in Melbourne and was doing the round Australia trip. But was travelling to fast for his plan. So we parted company the next morning.  I got to check out his tent and gear.  His tent was only 1.5Kg - was so envious!!  Mine weighed in at just over 3kg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the day that one set of clothes died. The shirt and shorts had rotted too much, and had too many holes in them by this time. With it damp, and no chance to dry them it wasn't going to be safe to wear them another day.  Now they were both worn when I started, so it was to be expected. Still it was a bit sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guthalungra to Alligator Creek:  Stopped in Home Hill for a bit, but had the "want to keep pedaling" urge. So kept going. It was still showering on and off.  I was in a mood that I just wanted to get North.  Was wondering about this cycle touring business. And probably more importantly was tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alligator Creek to Kennedy. This was my biggest day. 197km. A definite "keep pedaling". Though the travelling after Ingham was not energetic. I had planned to wild camp outside of Cardwell - but it was low lying land and very very wet. Yes it was still showering, but there had been recent heavy rains I was told, and all the water was still lying about the land.  I thought about cycling up and down the road to get 200km for the day - but was too tired to be bothered to do this. I also thought that I could have finished the trip to my parents that day by continuing to cycle as it was only 70km to go - but arriving after 9pm would have been a problem for my folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It rained during the night and I was clear that my tent was leaking again!!! Hard to miss the large drops hitting you in the head. Doh!!! Moved over and then put a container for the drops to splat in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kennedy to Parents Place :)  Managed to get a leech on me riding along the road. How was that possible - did it drop from the sky - or is it a gliding variety?  Met a Scottish couple just outside of Silkwood. The first that I've meet travelling south.  They had wet gear on. I didn't. It was cooler riding in the rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay so now that I'm here, now what?  Title of this post says it all. Just stopping pedaling for a couple of days now has improved my thinking. I was travelling fast. Too fast in hindsight.  A bit obsessive compulsive of me. In future need to have more rest stops and not go so far each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts of me a sore and hurt. Legs felt a bit tired. But with the 197km day that was to be expected. Bum wasn't as  bad as you might think  - I was used to the saddle. Been on that one for years now. Bit tender, but nothing that painful.  My left shoulder hurts. Pinched or twisted something and it hurt for most of the ride. Colin when trying my bike commented that the position was a lot of weight on the arms. This might be right - will have to look at this and change the riding position. I notice that my new grips - the right hand one has a worn spot, the left one not-&amp;gt; me leaning more on my right side to take the weight of the left arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to send my tent back for another warranty claim. My Thermarest is also in problems - so it goes also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about vans and travelling with petrol/diesel for stretches of the ride. But now that I'm rested, sanity has returned. I'm looking at how to lower the weight of the gear I have, and perhaps increase the luggage carrying to have more luxuries with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that I found important on the ride - being able to dry my clothes. This would have been helped if I'd stopped and rested more days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to sit out of the rain and away from all the ants. Some places lying on the ground out of the tent wasn't comfortable for all the ants that wanted to check me out for food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books - I missed reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charging the mobile - I had ebooks, but the phone needed charging at times. This is part of the reason for the missed posts. Stopping and resting would have helped this also. But will sort out some charging off the dynamo for next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to chuck out the stuff that sat in the bottom of my panniers - or at least examine it closely. If it didn't see use in a month of the east coast - what was I carrying it for still!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water purification - will look at some filters to see how to get water from all the ground sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, at the moment sitting about, eating, looking at new bike frames like Surly Big Dummy and Xtracycles. Looking at two wheeled trailers. There are bicycle mobile homes. Thinking of options.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Yuba Mundo Arrives</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/05/2010-05-25-yuba-mundo-arrives/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-05-25T19:56:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-05-25T19:56:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-05-25:/posts/2010/05/2010-05-25-yuba-mundo-arrives/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Due to a one thing and another, and Ben and I exchanging emails all of last week, and my frame didn't leave the shop until Friday 21st May. Fedex estimated a delivery date of 31st. I was hopeful, but thought it might take longer, but checked their tracking site almost …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Due to a one thing and another, and Ben and I exchanging emails all of last week, and my frame didn't leave the shop until Friday 21st May. Fedex estimated a delivery date of 31st. I was hopeful, but thought it might take longer, but checked their tracking site almost hourly :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning it surprised me. While I was thinking it was just leaving Sydney, it arrived. How is that possible - from USA to the middle of no where so quick. Four days!!! I order stuff in Australia, and it takes longer than that. Needless to say, I'm very happy right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasted no time unpacking and starting assembly. Thanks heaps Ben. It was well wrapped and padded in the box. It was so exciting unwrapping each item and finding what was there. I can't say enough good things about Ben at Yuba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See below for all unpacking images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally it was unwrapped and on the floor. Initial impression - its solid. Just what I ordered. I'm happy with the  finish - it is what it is. A good value, cargo bike frame. For the record, there were no scratches on the paint before I started. But as this is going to get a work out touring, I'll be buying some touch up paint at some point. I also assembled with the help of grease. My reasoning is this is a metal frame, its going to spend pretty much all its life outside, a bit of grease on parts will help slow any rust down. The insides of the frame will also get a squirt of something oily also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First order was getting wide loaders on. Then start to transfer other components from my MTB to it. Wide loaders just went on without any problems. Just slide on and tighten up the bolts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then things got interesting. Some things I thought would be a problem, weren't. Others that I thought would be no problem at all - are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the problems - at the moment two standing out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had planned on using my existing front hydraulic brake, and was leaning towards just using v-brakes on the back to get rolling. But the front hose hose is too short, and its going to need a ton of spacers and longer bolts to fit the caliper. That blew the option of getting it ridable. Time to either get a new front brake, or find spacers and a longer hose. Thinking about it now, I was probably overly optimistic thinking I could use my existing front brake - it was for a very special fork setup, and I did want to raise the handle bars on that bike anyway - so of course the brake hose would be too short!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next was the Rohloff.  I ordered the axle adapters as the Mundo dropouts are 14mm and the Rohloff axles are 10mm. After taking a drill to the adapters, they fit the axle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to drop the wheel in. I had thought that I'd just drop the wheel in, make an clamp to hold the torsion arm, and be done. This isn't to be. Using the torsion arm and external gear mech on this frame, it is not going to work. Both parts need to be below the frame and so don't fit together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dropouts are 7mm steel plate. Looking from the rear with the wheel out, the left hand dropout is flush with the tubing the forms the frame. The right hand side is mounted about the middle of the tubing. This means that there is only the width of the dropout, before the tube bulges out. On the other side of the tube is the disk mount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a lot playing with different angles on the axle plate I have, I think that either the OEM axle plate will just work, or the OEM2 axle plate will work with some help. Not 100% certain just yet. I need to find dimensions for the Rohloff drop outs to see how they compare to what metal is available on the Mundo. The Mundo dropouts are long with lots of thick steel - so the OEM is probably going to be the best bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be taking a welder to the frame though what ever happens. With lots of putting the back wheel in, and taking it back out again, the axle adapters got annoying real fast. They are small, round, and both want to drop off when your not expecting it, and roll away. The other thing that bugged me about them is that the drop out is 7mm thick, but the axle adapters are 4mm wide. I'd like to get a bit more axle in the dropout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More installing tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the pics I took:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528001_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528001_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528002_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528002_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528003_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528003_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528004_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528004_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528005_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528005_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528006_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528006_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528007_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528007_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528008_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528008_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528009_2529.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/25052010_2528009_2529.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Waiting for parts.</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/05/2010-05-28-waiting-for-parts/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-05-28T16:35:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-05-28T16:35:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-05-28:/posts/2010/05/2010-05-28-waiting-for-parts/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-28-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-28-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hopes of being quickly mobile failed.
The Monkeys &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org"&gt;Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt; for http://www.cheekytransport.com.au&lt;/sup&gt;
to the rescue. Called and spoke with Nic. They'll make up the hoses to length, bleed em, and have it all in the post next week.Love those guys!
&lt;a href="http://www.rohloff.com.au/"&gt;Rohloff Australia&lt;/a&gt;
are sending …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-28-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-28-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hopes of being quickly mobile failed.
The Monkeys &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org"&gt;Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt; for http://www.cheekytransport.com.au&lt;/sup&gt;
to the rescue. Called and spoke with Nic. They'll make up the hoses to length, bleed em, and have it all in the post next week.Love those guys!
&lt;a href="http://www.rohloff.com.au/"&gt;Rohloff Australia&lt;/a&gt;
are sending a new axle plate and disk rotor. With luck enough gear will arrive next week to let me pedal around the cane paddocks. Until then, having to content myself with sitting on the seat, and dreaming of the road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Rohloff bits arrive</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/05/2010-05-31-rohloff-bits-arrive/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-05-31T18:26:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-05-31T18:26:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-05-31:/posts/2010/05/2010-05-31-rohloff-bits-arrive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new axle plate makes mounting the wheel a lot easier.  Will wait until I sort out the disk before making the dropouts 10mm. When I narrow the dropouts, I'll add a bit more metal for the torque plate to press against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-31-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-31-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if the 160mm rotor will work …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new axle plate makes mounting the wheel a lot easier.  Will wait until I sort out the disk before making the dropouts 10mm. When I narrow the dropouts, I'll add a bit more metal for the torque plate to press against.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-31-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-31-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if the 160mm rotor will work. The amount of rotor that is available at the disk mount looks a bit short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could get a few millimeters more by making the dropout deeper, but not to much more, else the axle nuts will hit the tube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not the first to have hassles with the rear disk mount.  I'm hoping that it will not take me too long to sort out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-31-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-05-31-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-11 07:08&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mr Colostomy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to have an internal gear hub on my Mundo, but the ones in my price range aren't rated for any serious loads.  its a shame because I love the gear hubs on my other bikes, even if they are just 3 speeds.  Did you consider the Nuvinci CVP hub before deciding on the Rohloff?  I think I may one day put one of those on mine, partly because they are cheaper and partly because the idea of continuously variable transmission intrigues me (plus it has been done before on the Long Walk To Green blog and held up to heavy loads well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish you the best of luck with your build, and once you take it out for a spin I think you will enjoy the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-12 16:03&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn't think about any other hub. I had the Rohloff already. I've used Rohloff hubs in load bikes before. Friends have also. Never had a problem. Some of the bikes had way more load, and way stronger riders powering them, than I am. So the hub is built to last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-13 06:51&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Megan.  Good blog.  Makes me want to ride more......&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I too have a V3- its awesome- Likely a good choice for being tough when you aren't consumed with weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mine is pretty bare bones, however, external gears and vee brakes.  I have custom fitted aluminium checkplate to the rear rack and sideloaders, added Sweetskinz tires, Electra chrome plated fenders, and a Rolling  Jackass centrestand.  Maybe discs later this year.....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I get a front rack on my V3 I will post some pics somewhere. Will be following your Rohloff build. Cheers from Canada's west coast. John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Brakes arrive</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-11-brakes-arrive/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-11T11:35:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-11T11:35:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-11:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-11-brakes-arrive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100611.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100611.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the trip to the postoffice, saw me return with a large box. First thing was to fit the rear - as it was probably the one that was going to be the problem. Arrrg...It still is a problem :( The 160mm Rohloff rotor is too small (Well that or the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100611.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100611.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the trip to the postoffice, saw me return with a large box. First thing was to fit the rear - as it was probably the one that was going to be the problem. Arrrg...It still is a problem :( The 160mm Rohloff rotor is too small (Well that or the disk mount is too high.) I had suspected that before, but was assured that it would all be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing the adapter when I realised that I had two different sized ones, helped slightly, but not enough. Still too little disk rotor is under the pads. And still too much for me to "fix" by changes to the dropouts. Not happy. I could have ordered a larger rotor earlier, and not be sitting now waiting again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-11-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-11-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;sighs&lt;/em&gt; more waiting time. Need to order a larger rotor. Rohloff don't do a 180mm or 185mm any more, so its either 190mm or 203mm. Yuba recommended a 180mm Rotor, so I'm going to go with the 190mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, more daily trips to the post office waiting for a larger rotor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front fits without any dramas. So I've one brake. Might fit up the chain and have bit of a ride about on the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>New Rotor arrives</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-15-new-rotor-arrives/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-15T17:09:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-15T17:09:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-15:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-15-new-rotor-arrives/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100615.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100615.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new rotor arrived today. Its actually the 190mm Magura option from Rohloff. As I guessed, it is a bit big for the caliper to bolt onto. Yuba recommending a 180mm for the rear. I think a 185 would be just spot on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I ordered the frame, I also …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100615.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100615.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new rotor arrived today. Its actually the 190mm Magura option from Rohloff. As I guessed, it is a bit big for the caliper to bolt onto. Yuba recommending a 180mm for the rear. I think a 185 would be just spot on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I ordered the frame, I also I ordered the adapter from Yuba for the rear 180mm disk. Looking at it now, its way too small. The brakes arrived with two different size adapters - 1 small  (that almost matches the Yuba one),  and one larger - that works better on the rear. Better, but not perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image above has the caliper resting down onto the top of the rotor. This is with the axle adapters on the Rohloff hub, in the 14mm dropouts. At both ends its about 5mm to bolt flat to the adapter. (Its easier to see the gap on the front bolt.) This will sort its self out tomorrow when the dropouts get narrowed. I'll get some more metal at the bottom of each dropout - and the rotor will drop downward. I might also put some spacers between the adapter, and the caliper to fine tune the height - to get it just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited now - this is all stuff that can be done by me - so there is not more waiting for parts to arrive. Baring any unexpected developments, I should be able to have a ride tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-16 04:42&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are close!  I had a similar experience with Hayes hydraulics on a Kona Mtb- acutally found some thick aluminum washers to shim the calipers up so my pads were contacting the disc perfectly.  As you say, your dropouts rework gives you latitude to adjust this.  J.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-16 10:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes it looks like your close to getting rear disc brakes on a Yuba (one of a very small elite group in the world I think!). Loving the blog (more pics please!) and great to see another Mundo builder in Australia. You seem to have the new style of rear disc mount (on my V3 the 2 holes are parallel to the frame) which is no doubt making the process easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-16 18:35&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll try to remember and take more pictures. I know that I'm slack with taking pics. If there is anything you want an image of, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked your blog also - read that lots to try and work out what disks you had tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>A Disk brake Mundo</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-16-a-disk-brake-mundo/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-16T18:29:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-16T18:29:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-16:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-16-a-disk-brake-mundo/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a lot longer than I thought, but then I got the wheel back in and the disks are on. 160mm front, 190mm rear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning was lots of assembling  and disassembling it all, checking with small spacers the amount of metal to add in. I had forgotten about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took a lot longer than I thought, but then I got the wheel back in and the disks are on. 160mm front, 190mm rear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning was lots of assembling  and disassembling it all, checking with small spacers the amount of metal to add in. I had forgotten about the axle adapter I had on yesterday  - that was an extra 2mm. All up the wheel dropped down 7mm from the original dropout spot. I ended up getting a 14mm bolt, filing the grove for the 10mm axle, and brazing that in the dropout. Then a 4mm plate on the long part of the dropout slot at the rear to get the whole thing to 10mm.  Lots of filing today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works, but its still going to be a bit fiddly to change the wheel. The wheel will not just drop in or out. The axle plate on the Rohloff hits the chain stay tube when at the front of the dropout. With the 14mm dropouts, I didn't notice this as there is more room on both sides for it to all move about. With the dropouts being 10mm, its noticeable. If I put the 4mm on the opposite side (the front of the dropout slot) it would have been better. Putting the wheel in or out, there is some jiggling, and rotating the external gear mech and the OEM axle adaptor, before it all drops in (or out). I'm not about to change it now. I don't need to get the wheel on/off that often, and its not that hard to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did have a moment of wondering if the 203mm disk would be a just bolt on. There is enough room for it. Decided not to try it - as I didn't want to wait more days for a rotor and adapter.  Also had a wonder if there was another size caliper adapter that I could have used instead. Anyway if at some time in the future I want to change it, the bits added in can all be ground out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chain - I wanted to have the chain tensioner pushing up, but it didn't work out. The chain hits on the wide loader. Down still works. Don't know how many links on the chain, and I'm not counting them. I'm running 39/16 cogs, with 165mm cranks. Ended up using a half link to get the length just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as I finished, it started raining - and hasn't stopped. So there was a very short ride in the liquid sunshine.. The brakes feel a bit spongy. Need to ride a bit more to see if that is a real problem, or just my perception of them. Both hoses are too long. The front has way too much hose. Not sure if this affects the brake feeling. Will check this out more when its not raining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather encourages getting mudguards on next. They will not go on easily. Brake calipers are in the way. Can make up short adapters to fix this, but am also thinking about making up some wider guards. I running 1.35 tires on at the moment, at some point I might want to got bigger. I'd like to not have hassles with mud guards then. Going to go hunt about tomorrow and see whats available. Corflute would be handy right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image2.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-16-image2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also will put a piece of tube over the chain runs - as I want to try and keep muck off the chain as much as possible. It will also help keep the  bottom run from slapping against the frame. Ideal would be fully enclosed chain running in oil, but that's to hard to do. But any covering has to help with keeping the chain clean. Certainly will help with keeping me clean. I have a piece of 13mm poly tube, but want to try with a larger size. Another thing for tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of interest, I wondered what the load limit on the Rohloff is. Ended up sending Rohloff an email last night asking. The answer is; there isn't any - but you do have to honor the gearing limits they set. So I can pick up as much stuff as I want - long as I can pedal it. That works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-16 23:13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mr Colostomy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience with brand new disc brakes is that it takes time for all of the little imperfections on the pads to wear off, and all the little imperfections in the rotor to be impressed upon the pads. Once this has happened the effective surface area of the rotor is increased and the braking power improves a lot.  The same is true for drum brakes (although the break-in is shorter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-18 04:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good stuff.  Keep us posted.  I echo keller74's comments that your disc tab is different than my V3- with my holes essentially parallel to the chainstay.  Also I noticed threaded bosses on the downtube near the head on Jim's orange V3 that are not my V3.  For the bread rack I guess?  John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Chain Guard - first go.</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-17-chain-guard-first-go/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-17T18:14:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-17T18:14:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-17:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-17-chain-guard-first-go/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not really a lot happened to day. I hunted for some pipe for the chain guard, and mud guards. The large diameter pipe tents to be heavy because of the thicker walls. Didn't get that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-17-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-17-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chain guard - ended up trying electrical conduit. I wanted a tube over the top …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not really a lot happened to day. I hunted for some pipe for the chain guard, and mud guards. The large diameter pipe tents to be heavy because of the thicker walls. Didn't get that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-17-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-17-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chain guard - ended up trying electrical conduit. I wanted a tube over the top chain run, and the bottom.  Spent most of the day heating, bending, filing, assembling and disassembling the chain. I don't want the chain guard rubbing on the hub. With careful bending and filing - I did acheive that, and still had the tube bending in to enclose the chain. I think this was a waste of effort now. It took a long time, and really doesn't do that much for the guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial try had a bend on both ends. The conduit has some flex - but the problem was getting the chain linked up. I find it easier to link the chain on the chain ring. This didn't allow that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chopped the front off - and shortened the back. But not sure if I'm happy with it at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-17-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-17-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I experimented with using just floating pipes over the two chain runs. Thinking about doing that, and leaving the chain ring free. Also thinking of other ways to cover the chain ring up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have access to brazing gear and was going to add tabs on for the guard. But now, thinking to cable tied it on only until I'm sure. I'll sleep on it tonight and have another look tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Woo Hoo - riding</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-18-woo-hoo-riding/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-18T19:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-18T19:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-18:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-18-woo-hoo-riding/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100618.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100618.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My quick ride the other day was as a single speed. Decided today to quickly fix the gear changer and work that Rohloff. In a common story, it took way longer than I thought it would. The cable outers for the gear changer ended up being 1870mm long. Easy to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100618.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100618.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My quick ride the other day was as a single speed. Decided today to quickly fix the gear changer and work that Rohloff. In a common story, it took way longer than I thought it would. The cable outers for the gear changer ended up being 1870mm long. Easy to cut them - used side cutters and then filed them flat. The liners - scissors. Cutting the inners was hard. The two pairs of side cutters in the shed both didn't want to cut. They mushed and chewed. I thought about using a pair of scissors, but ended up using the grinder. It wasn't the best and I wished for proper cutters. I'm thinking to either buy a pair and carry them with me, or better yet, find a bike shop to precut some inners to the length I need. Arrggh - to do that I'd need to take the cables out and measure them. I don't know how much is inside the twist shifter. So, next time I have to change a cable - I'll try and remember to measure then, and then get them cut to length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly I had to put a side the nice thick tubed handle bar from Yuba. By the time the brake lever, shifter, and a small bit of grip went on, there was no space left for the bar ends. I did like the extra rise it gave. Used the old bar I had, but will look to replace it with a steel tube sometime. I through on the lights, and old mud guards, adjusted the seat height, and headed out for a longer ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brakes are starting to feel better. The front ended up getting some washers between the fork and the caliper to space it out far enough to adjust correctly.  The rear by careful design by me (yeah right! - pull the other one.) was spot on - no spacers needed.  By the time the rear hose was routed, it was okay for length. The front hose is really too long. I'll wait until I'm at a shop to shorten it. I don't want to risk not having a brake here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Yuba cargo bag goes on well. I was going to keep the space look to the frame, but now I'll find something to place on the sides and wide loaders. I want to try and stop lots of mud hitting the bags as I'll end up unclipped them and carrying them into the tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First trip - to the post office to collect the mail. Picture above is outside the post office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does it ride on the road - really good. Lots of gears - though didn't need any of the low gears here. Need to find some hills to test that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-18-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-18-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After riding about for a bit, I then returned to the chain guard. I need to replace my grandmothers bucket tomorrow.  I cut the bottom off it and placed it over the crank. I cut to more slots out to enable the base to sit as flat as possible against the frame (See the photo below). Its held in with two cable ties. Ideally, the distance up from the bottom of the bucket would be the same all the way around, but because the bucket is a bit soft, it doesn't sit vertically. I put the crank on, and slowly cut bits off until it could turn freely. Just cut anything that hits the crank arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-18-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-18-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the photo on the right, you can see the slots cut on the back, to help the base sit flat. Cut some slots for the chain and it was done.  Tomorrow I'll sort out the chain runs. Going to go look at poly tubing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guard isn't finished yet. I want to place a disk (I didn't want to upset people by taking another bucket) over the outside of the crank - so there is less of a gap, and to help that bit more with keeping pants clean. I tried with some long slacks on, it does a good job of keeping pants from the chain as it is. The bucket should be cheap - a harder plastic bowl may be better. Now I have a template to start with. I'm still thinking of other options. See what occurs to me tomorrow. I'll be going on a longer ride to the local town. Will be about 30+km round trip. Thinking time, and see how the bucket holds up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-18-image2.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-18-image2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heres another shot - it does look like it would do a wonderful job of keeping water/mud from the front wheel off the chain. Probably need to paint it - I'm not sure how long it would last in the sun otherwise.  Depending how long, and the cost of a bucket, it might stay the way it is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Longer ride</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-19-longer-ride/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-19T18:17:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-19T18:17:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-19:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-19-longer-ride/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Clocked up 40km today - would have done more, but the bottom bracket was unwinding itself and of all the tools I took with me, I didn't take the crank puller and bottom bracket socket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found that I need something on the top chain run - to stop the chain bouncing off …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Clocked up 40km today - would have done more, but the bottom bracket was unwinding itself and of all the tools I took with me, I didn't take the crank puller and bottom bracket socket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found that I need something on the top chain run - to stop the chain bouncing off on big bumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front wheel needs the
&lt;a href="http://yubaride.com/yubashop/31-deflopilator.html"&gt;deflopilator&lt;/a&gt;
. Annoyingly the front light provides the stop at the moment. I don't want to break the light. Bought a spring - but found it was too stretchy when I mounted it.. Will return it Monday  and try the stiffer one that I discounted as being too stiff. I'll also add a bracket around the light, to stop it hitting the frame - if the fork does turn around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Go-Getter bag is great. It swallows everything - from a bucket, to lengths of pipe. I did mess up a few tight spots and scraped wide loaders or the bag. That will resolve itself as I get used to the extra length. Not surprisingly I found that I couldn't bunny hop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Chain Guard - 2nd go</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-22-chain-guard-2nd-go/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-22T17:15:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-22T17:15:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-22:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-22-chain-guard-2nd-go/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100622.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100622.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chain is well covered now. From the chain ring to near the rear cog. The top tube does not rub on the chain or the cogs. The chain does rub on the bottom. Can't hear it from the saddle though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rode a few km on this trying to hit every …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100622.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100622.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chain is well covered now. From the chain ring to near the rear cog. The top tube does not rub on the chain or the cogs. The chain does rub on the bottom. Can't hear it from the saddle though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rode a few km on this trying to hit every puddle and mud spot I could find. So far its going okay. Going to hit some dirt roads tomorrow. Corrugations, clay soil, and with the rain up here, will be good an messy. A chance to see what is going to work loose, and if the chain guard really does that much for keeping the chain clean. It does keep the chain of long pants though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-22-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-22-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still tossing up if to mount a basket on the front, or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried a few more options for the deflopilator. Not really happy with that still. Its not the flopping that is the problem - its the light being hit. Getting a longer bolt to place a metal bracket around the light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-22-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-22-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View looking down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-25 08:06&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Mr Colostomy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd go for the basket,  I have one on my non-Yuba and whenever I am on the Yuba I miss it quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-25 17:50&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like a basket, but my handle bars don't seem to have much space. My current thinking is to use the two bolts and attach two small buckets(?) to the sides under the handle bar. This will give me space for small items and not interfere with the light, or with me seeing the front wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Guess what I found?</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-24-guess-what-i-found/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-24T17:37:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-24T17:37:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-24:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-24-guess-what-i-found/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been busy - riding about, doing small jobs. After weeks of waiting for parts to arrive, now I'm rushing to get everything done. Still waiting on a few things, but expecting them next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-24-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-24-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding about because its fun, and to test out chain guard, and find what wants to work …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been busy - riding about, doing small jobs. After weeks of waiting for parts to arrive, now I'm rushing to get everything done. Still waiting on a few things, but expecting them next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-24-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-24-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding about because its fun, and to test out chain guard, and find what wants to work loose. I think the chain guard is a winner. Looking at the amount of mud/sand/water splashing on the outside and on my feet, the chain is as clean as when it went on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been after some Corflute for a while. Haven't found anyone that sells it up here, but today, out riding I found some. A large sheet too! Today was windy. It was interesting riding home with this sheet - it alternated between anchor and sail modes. Most of the way was anchor :( Glad for the Yuba - was easy to tie it on the back - and pedal. Would have held it and rode one handed on the MTB. Go Yuba!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-24-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-24-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also acquired a piece of aluminium (6x60x300mm) and spent time on the hacksaw and file. Made one spanner for the headset bolts. The reason for the 'h' shape, is that I want to have a thick handle on the other spanner to use as a chain whip. 3 tools from one bit of aluminium. With these tools, I can do all maintenance and repairs. A wide jaw 6" shifter opens wide enough to go over the bottom bracket socket. It will also work on the Rohloff sprocket nut, and all other nuts on the bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also found the right tension spring for the
&lt;span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: #333333; font-family: Georgia, serif; font-size: 13px; line-height: 20px;"&gt;
deflopilator.  Its not the length that was important - its the tension - enough to pull the fork to center, but still have enough stretch to let the forks turn as far as you need them to, without over stretching the spring.  Its on now, but will change the mount when I get a longer bolt.  I'm not keen on rusty bolts - so all the bolts that I'm responsible for are marine grade stainless steel socket heads.  Makes life easy - no rust, and Allen keys.  There are a couple of bolts with nuts on the end - the front mudguard and light mount is one.  New bolt is on order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While wandering about the hardware shop for the spring, I found right angle grease nipples.  Going to fit these on the end of my pedals to lubricate the pedal bearings.  This will involve drilling a hole, and tapping the plastic cover that hides the nut at the end of the pedal axle.  One of tomorrows tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-25 14:59&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great stuff Megan.  Keep it coming.  Your post made me think of a trick I used long ago to grease pedals.  Just posted it on my blog.  Cheers, John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Greasing Pedals made easy</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-25-greasing-pedals-made/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-25T17:24:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-25T17:24:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-25:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-25-greasing-pedals-made/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fitted grease nipples to the pedals today. Just before I started, I thought about another idea - just drill a small hole in the cap, and use a syringe to force grease in. A variation of this is what John describes
&lt;a href="http://yubamundosforeveryone.blogspot.com/2010/06/grease-job.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
on his blog. I like the nipples with the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fitted grease nipples to the pedals today. Just before I started, I thought about another idea - just drill a small hole in the cap, and use a syringe to force grease in. A variation of this is what John describes
&lt;a href="http://yubamundosforeveryone.blogspot.com/2010/06/grease-job.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
on his blog. I like the nipples with the ball bearing in the end - blocks water and dirt entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've Shimano 324 pedals - SPD cleat one side, flat platform the other. I removed the cage around the pedals first. Drilled a hole in end cap 7.5mm wide. Used 8mm right angle grease nipple - and just screwed it into the hole. Refit the cage, and there is about 1mm gap between the cage and the nipple. When the grease is pushed in, the cap wants to pop off - but hits the cage 1mm later. I'm leaving it there. The whole job took less time then I've spent in the past trying to force grease into the pedal. Greasing the pedals is now soo much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added slash guards to the end of the mudguards. That bucket is coming in handy. Front guard, I'm not sure yet of the attachment - at the moment its hanging on with two bits of wire. Will see how it works riding before probably using cable ties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried also to make a disk for the outside of the chain ring out of the remains of the bucket - but the curve of the bucket defeated me in the end. Need a flat piece of plastic. Still one piece of bucket left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the excitement yesterday on the Corflute - and decided today not to use it. The sign is thick, has more weight than I'd like, but mainly it will interfere with access to the hub. Instead of this, I'm thinking to get some nylon type fabric. This will not hold water, should be lighter than the Corflute, and let me be creative with where it is placed. By tying it on in a few places, I'll still be able to access the hub without having to undo bolts. The main aim of it is to reduce mud splashing onto the Go-Getter bags, so they're not as filthy when I take them into the tent at nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made another 'h' spanner today and put a length of chain on the handle for a chain whip. Not 100% happy with the chain whip part. But used the two spanners to tighten the head-stem nuts - so proving that they work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Action shot time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drilled hole in pedal after the cage is out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blury picture of the grease nipple fitted. Didn't totally remove the cage - just the two outside bolts, and loosened the other two to swing it to the side. I left the nipple pointing slightly forward and is up towards the cleat side of the pedal. The cage is lower on that side. I wanted to use the platform side, but then there isn't much room to get the grease gun in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image2.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got enough grease in there now. If I can find a road racer tube, I want to see if it will go over the seal end of the pedal. That seal isn't the best on these pedals. Any help it can get would be good. Will hunt about for a length tomorrow when I visit the not so local bike shop. A thought I just had now, was to use a bit of coke can aluminium. Might try that first - coke cans are common, and means I don't have to take the pedal off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image3.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image3.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front splash guard showing its bucket origins. It can swing on its attachment point. Not sure yet if it will swing too much when riding at speed and be useless. If so, will weight it a bit. Also want to check if it will be a problem when going through pot holes. A piece of truck tube might be better here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image4.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-25-image4.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear splash guard - not so obviously a bucket bit. My rear guard is just a bit short, and the light gets coated with mud. Not good. The splash guard should stop that. At the bottom is a piece of 19mm water pipe inserted in the end of the Mudo frame. It plugs the holes, and I have a vague idea of using it to attach a piece of  Corflute to - to extend the mud guard all the way down. I need to find a thinner sign first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-26 03:29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I thought you were on the driest continent on earth!  I like the syringe idea- you could carry one of those with you, whereas packing a real grease gun is a bit much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have also seen people extend their fenders (mudguards) by slicing a cheaper cycling waterbottle in half. (only the yuba logo would be upside down then.....)Best,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-26 04:52&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not carry a grease gun. Easy enough to find a workshops/service station with one. The pedals only need greasing about once a year. Carrying a syringe of grease would also have be a problem - most grease that I've seen for sale, is in containers larger than a syringe. Too much hassle for a once a year lube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia is the driest continent, but right now, I'm in the middle of the wettest areas. Nearby Tully has an average annual rainfall that exceeds 4 meters. Record is over 8 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-26 09:44&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really enjoying all your progress and ingenuity. Side boards on my mundo do make getting to the the hub and brakes annoying (I use an electric screwdriver to make it a bit easier). Soft and light sounds good. My wooden boards are great but the brake side one interfered with my disc brake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the front mudguards you may have checked my blog on it (there's a link to a more elegant solution too)  keller74.wordpress.com/2010/02/09/mudguards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-26 18:21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did check out your blog. But found that I didn't have a problem with the front mud guard. I've a longer bolt, and a spacer. The mud guard mount goes around the caliper and mounts where it  should. I'll get a picture to make it clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided not to go with the boards - using a tarp.  No sewing required, light, water proof and cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Just about done.</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-26-just-about-done/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-26T18:54:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-26T18:54:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-26:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-26-just-about-done/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just about finished building.  Did some riding in the rain (again). Slash guards worked well. Will keep them on. Much cleaner feet at the end of the day. Cleaner bike also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100626.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100626.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided not to use cloth around the Go-Getters. That would involve a lot of sewing - edges and eyelet holes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just about finished building.  Did some riding in the rain (again). Slash guards worked well. Will keep them on. Much cleaner feet at the end of the day. Cleaner bike also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100626.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100626.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided not to use cloth around the Go-Getters. That would involve a lot of sewing - edges and eyelet holes. Although I've a 5000m of thread. I don't want to wait about here to get all that done. In a moment of thinking - bought a small tarp. Cost less than $4. Promptly doubled its value by putting a few more eyelets around the edge. Its big enough to go over the rack, down the sides, and up a short way on the outside.  There is also a bit to cover the ends. I'm thinking to run a string through the eyelets and use some ocky straps across the top to hold it all together.  I haven't tried it with the bags yet (tomorrow), but it looks like it will do the job of keeping mud of them. I can also use it as a rain shelter when not riding. When I ordered the frame and got the Go-Getters, I did think about using a tarp then - kind of like the Xtracycle Freeloader bags. Wasn't sure, and the Go-Getters were a great price, and they are huge!!.  I like being able to open the top and dump Stuff in. Shut the lid and its  water proof. The Go-Getters are well thought out - with buckles, and bits of velcro in the right places to pin extra strap up off the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also decided not to cover the chain any further. If I put a disk on the chain ring, there will only be a couple of inches of chain free at the rear cog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used a piece of water pipe found on the side of the road to stop the fork swinging right around and bashing the light. Its cut so that the wheel can be almost at right angles - something that shouldn't happen riding. The spring under neath keeps the wheel straight when the bike is on the center stand. Still having problems with that spring - the extra long hoses push the wheel slightly to the right - no much, but precludes hands off riding. Changing the location of the hoses helps - but will wait until I can shorten them before playing with the spring again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found a Red Bull can on the side of the road - used that to make some sleeves around the seal on the pedal. Red Bull cans are very thin. The join is is made like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  _________  
  \  
   \  \ 
 ______\ 
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When squashed flat - its secure against popping open. Cause to take the pedals off - it has to be pulled off. Tins are common along the road side. Use scissors to cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image2.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chain guard does a great job of keeping mud off the chain. All this would have ended up a grinding past on the chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image3.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-06-26-image3.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-09-12 07:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Meg. I found your blog as I was searching ways to tune up my Yuba Mundo for a long bike tour. My destination is central asia "stans". I've only one and half months to repare  myself and the bike before I go. I don't have fancy components but your blog still has a lot of valuable information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example your experience with Go-Getters was that they are too big. Good to know that since I was allmost going to buy them. Now I'll buy Ortlieb packs that are half the size. I'll also buy heavy duty rims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up my own blog, it's called endless-upphill.blogspot.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect, KAI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>And I'm away...</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/06/2010-06-29-and-im-away/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-06-29T06:35:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-06-29T06:35:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-06-29:/posts/2010/06/2010-06-29-and-im-away/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, heading off later today. I could do more stuff on the bike - but to impatient to get going. I never intended to stop here this long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to say that I'm well organised, and everything is ready to just pedal off after breakfast this morning, but I'm not …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, heading off later today. I could do more stuff on the bike - but to impatient to get going. I never intended to stop here this long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to say that I'm well organised, and everything is ready to just pedal off after breakfast this morning, but I'm not. This morning will be the quickly throw everything in to the Go-Getters. Fill the water bottles - not that much. Going to peel a few coconuts that are here - only thought of this last night. Say goodbye to family. Endure the usual - why don't you catch a bus/train/fly routine, etc.. I expect to get on the road by mid morning. Later than I'd like - but things to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is down as mostly fine - but all the forecasts have showers from tomorrow for further than I'll be travelling in the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road ahead is pretty much all up hill. Heading up the Palmerston highway towards Ravenshoe. There will be detours on the way, so not expecting to get there super quick. Unless my detours don't exist. Yep - Google maps isn't 100% accurate. Telling my brother the back roads I was planning on taking yesterday - he let me know that they don't exist any more - bridges gone, roads fenced off, or plain no road to start with. Actually this last is true - looking about here Google maps shows roads that I know aren't there. But we'll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More updates from along the way...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-06-30 09:58&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound like a great time ahead. I'm facinated to see how the Mundo performs on this sort of trip. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>And back again...</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/07/2010-07-01-and-back-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-01T10:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-07-01T10:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-07-01:/posts/2010/07/2010-07-01-and-back-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-01-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-01-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it was up, up, up, then down, down down. Yep, day one was all uphill. Second day was coasting back down again. The escape was probably doomed for a several reasons. Mainly for lack of fully loaded practice ride I think. Problems started from lack of planning;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-01-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-01-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it was up, up, up, then down, down down. Yep, day one was all uphill. Second day was coasting back down again. The escape was probably doomed for a several reasons. Mainly for lack of fully loaded practice ride I think. Problems started from lack of planning;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger of the large Go-Getters is that you can fool yourself into leave packing until the end, thinking that you can throw it all in the bags. And you can. However, the packing doesn't get that much scrutiny with this method. On checking during the inevitable repack on the road I found that I had things that should never have made it onto the bags in the first place -&amp;gt; metal files, spray tins of paint, large squirt gun tubes of glue, saws, more than once set of some tools, rolls of leather, etc. There were bags wrapped in plastic, that I wasn't game to open, for fear of what I'd find inside them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-01-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-01-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such large bags, everyone feels that you have space to carry - well everything. I had planned to take some back roads, figuring on about 4 days between towns. I had some pasta, soup, dried peas, sultanas for this. I stopped and repacked when it started to shower - as I'd just left bags sitting on the back rack. I ended up with over half of one Go-Getters filled with food! This is an insane amount for one person. Not only that, but some of the stuff was straight out of the fridge - damp - wrapped in plastic, in panniers, in the sun (when it appeared - always when creeping upwards), was making for a soup. I consumed way more than I wanted that night and next morning, trying to avoid mould, and to free up space. I don't think you can claim lightening of the load, when you eat it... I still had stuff that went back in the fridge when I returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun when it was out - I had a thermometer, it hit close to 40 before I noticed and put it under cover. Humidity was up there - I was a mass of sweat. The day was a mix of showers, sun, showers. I didn't bother with wet gear - was wet enough from sweating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is the chain tensioner which is causing problems. It had been behaving without a problem in test rides, but it didn't play well with the loaded bags. Something was slipping/jumping. I don't think it is the hub - as it has never skipped before, and has 3000km on it. If I pretended I had a single speed - the chain would not skip if I was travelling slow enough, no matter what the gear. Chain skip occured more in the higher gears than the low. The low gears, I had to be spinning crazyily to have it happen. My thinking is that at the faster speed, the road bumps gave the chain that bit more bounce, to press outwards just enough enough to jump a tooth or two. I've taken the chain guard off to see better what's happening - but that far back, its hard to see. I tried to simimulate the problem pedalling with the front brake on - but unless I go fast enough, there isn't a problem.  So, going to change the chain tensioner to the two wheel versions. This will cause the chain to hang lower, destroying my nice chain line, but such is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update this morning: I went for a ride with the usual ride stuff on and had no problems - much as I tried. Returned and had someone sit on the back and watch while I pedaled, then we swapped. Me pedaling,  it would skip. Hard to tell what it is though. When I was on the back, it only happened a couple times. Neither of us could see the chain jumping  - but it is hard to tell. Feels like and sounds like its jumping a link. I do have a half link and a joiner link, but it can happen too often for it to be those two links - which are at the same spot. Need to be moving to have it happen. Going to change the tensioner, change the chain - remove the half link and the joiner link, change the oil in the hub. See what that gives. Hope it isn't the hub, but still think that it can't be - its given 3000km of trouble free usage, though admittedly, I've probably not loaded it with 80kg plus of weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's no denying it was a heavy load. For instance, with all the food only in one Go-Getter, I could not pick it up one handed. Thats before adding on the tent, tools, junk and water. The bags fully loaded - were a struggle to even pick up. But I wasn't out of space to stack more stuff on if I wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did it handle - like a dream (not the nightmare ones). Yes you could feel it was heavy - I used low gear lots - just sit and spin. Skipping chain helped with this - I had to resist my temptation to push harder gears. It bounced happily over railway lines and pot holes I didn't manage to avoid. It didn't feel unstable. There was no flex - standing an pedalling was - well, just like standing and pedalling on your bike. Better than my MTB with rack and gear - the rack used to sway. No sway here. Downhill speeds of just over 50km/hr didn't present any problems either - stable at speed.  A benefit of the weight I think is that semitrailers and B-doubles didn't blow me about.  The upright seating is a real bonus - much easier on my arms and shoulders. Though, for only two days that isn't saying a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the end I had the choice of pushing on for a small town to sit and wait for a different chain tensioner, or retuning to base (so to speak). It seemed a better idea to return.  It was it was downhill, I could off load the stuff on my family for them to use, and the local council helped with my choice. They were spraying from the camp ground up the road. I spent some time waiting for them to get away, but after pedalling up for a bit, I caught up to them. Then they stayed just infront of me.  I didn't want to breath poison spray all day following them. So turned downhill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One nice thing - riding along, looking over the side into the water - saw a platypus swimming along.  Only got to see it as I was going slow along the edge of the road. No chance of any motorist seeing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-07-01 16:24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Megan.  Good post.  Ohh, to be cruising around Qlnd listening to Redgum bootlegs on your walkman.  Gosh, dating myself now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like the Go-Getter bags are awesome: One just has to adopt minamalist behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could your skipping problem be because you fit a new xtra long chain to the Mundo and retained the old cog on the Rolhoff hub?  What happens is as the chain stretches the chain and the rear cog wear in together, if you fit a new chain without replacing the cog you get a skipping effect under heavy load.  New chain, new cogs.  New cog for those lucky enough to have internal gears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-07-02 06:43&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was wondering this also - the chain is one new, one that was on the MTB. It had slight wear. I will try this though. Getting two new chains is easy enough. Can reverse the Rohloff sprocket and the front chainring also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did an oil change on the Rohloff yesterday. The oil out was dark colored. The one that went is is clear. So not sure what this means in the scheme of things. Haven't tested if this helps yet, as afterwards I didn't have anyone around to provide a load. Unloaded its no problem. So will ride into town today and get two new chains and try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Sorting it out</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/07/2010-07-02-sorting-it-out/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-02T16:41:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-07-02T16:41:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-07-02:/posts/2010/07/2010-07-02-sorting-it-out/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got a helpful body to sit on the back rack again, trying to see if the chain tension is a problem. Got him to put his boot on the tensioner to really tension it. Did this or the oil change help? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talked with guys at
Cheeky Transport &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org"&gt;Wayback Machine …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got a helpful body to sit on the back rack again, trying to see if the chain tension is a problem. Got him to put his boot on the tensioner to really tension it. Did this or the oil change help? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talked with guys at
Cheeky Transport &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org"&gt;Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt; for http://www.cheekytransport.com.au&lt;/sup&gt;
to see if they had any further suggestions on the plan of attach, and to give them the heads up if didn't have any joy after trying on my own.  I also talked with Maria at
&lt;a href="http://www.rohloff.com.au/"&gt;Rohloff Australia&lt;/a&gt;
She was very helpful; suggesting what to look at that have caused people problems in the past; chains, sprockets, joiner links, overly tight or loose nut tensions,  etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slipping I'm having only happens with heavy load on. It didn't happen when I had the hub in the MTB touring. One reason I'm still going to change the tensioner and look at chains and sprockets. On the MTB I didn't run a tensioner- having slotted dropouts, so could move the wheel back. Load on the MTB rack was probably in the 40kg range. I figured my two loaded Go-Getters were in the 60-80kg range. My helpful body load is over 100kg. He wouldn't say how heavy he is, but was socked when I asked if he is  less than the 200kg Mundo rack limit. He assures me he is :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Result: I'm going to try all the easy stuff first; changing the chain tensioner to a Rohloff one. I'll  get two new chains,  no half or joiner link, and new chain ring and sprocket. (well swap them around). If that gives no joy, then will send the hub back to Rohloff to have a look at under warranty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracked down a torque wrench and spent some time this afternoon checking bolts that I've touched on the external gear mech, OEM adaptor plate, and axle nuts. Found I had everything too loose. Wasn't that surprised on the smaller bolts - I was worried about doing damage making them too tight without the torque wrench. The axle nuts - I was surprised how tight they get done up. I've had problems with the nuts working loose before - so guess now they are tight. Will wait for the tensioner and new chains before trying a heavy load again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also had a go with the oxy - and plugged up one leak in the frame. What's this about? I put all stainless button head bolts with washers in all the braze-on's on the Mundo - to stop water entry.  There are lots of them, which is really handy. As I was doing this I squirted some light oil in the frame. I noticed that it leaked out of two on the rack. It looked like that when the weld went around the tube, they missed by pin prick meeting up to the start of the weld. A drop of braze to plug it up. I put some more oil in after this, but found I missed sealing one of them. Will do that one again tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to waiting on parts to arrive, before testing it all. In the mean time - time to go riding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-07-06 12:26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the chain tensioner adjustable for alignment? ( I don't know much about these) I could guess that alignment might be more of an issue at speed and under load. Just a thought. You'll figure it out I'm sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Tensioner arrives, wheel departs</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/07/2010-07-06-tensioner-arrives-wh/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-06T19:24:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-07-06T19:24:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-07-06:/posts/2010/07/2010-07-06-tensioner-arrives-wh/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rohloff.de/en/products/speedhub/chain_tensioner/"&gt;Rohloff Tensioner&lt;/a&gt;
arrived today. Its a much stronger item then my last tensioner, and it gives a lot more chain wrap around the sprocket. My last tensioner feels like a tired rubber band compared to the Rohloff one. The Rohloff tensioner comes with spacers to adjust the alignment; so the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rohloff.de/en/products/speedhub/chain_tensioner/"&gt;Rohloff Tensioner&lt;/a&gt;
arrived today. Its a much stronger item then my last tensioner, and it gives a lot more chain wrap around the sprocket. My last tensioner feels like a tired rubber band compared to the Rohloff one. The Rohloff tensioner comes with spacers to adjust the alignment; so the wheel on the tensioner ends up directly in line with the sprocket. Two new SRAM 9 speed chains, bit of playing with the length to get the jockey wheel in the right location according to the docs, and I was done. Short ride about all is good. Throw 120kg on the rack and same problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had talked with
&lt;a href="http://www.rohloff.com.au/"&gt;Rohloff Australia&lt;/a&gt;
about this before, so packed up the whole wheel and posted it off. Lots of bubble wrap around the hub, with tape to keep it on. The wheel was left on also to help the rim. I was surprised
&lt;a href="http://auspost.com.au/"&gt;Australia Post&lt;/a&gt;
would would handle it. Glad they did. If the item is too large to sent via
&lt;a href="http://auspost.com.au/"&gt;AusPost&lt;/a&gt;
, your in for a job finding someone to send it. I found that none of the courier companies up here - TNT, IPEC would just take a parcel off you -&amp;gt; you need an account first. Obviously your not going to have one unless your sending parcels regularly. One guy suggested checking with the buss companies. Yep, buss companies handle freight. With an extra $9.90 for courier delivery at the other end. So if your stuck - check out the busses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I'll be sans bike for a few days, got the spray can out and touched up the paint job from my brazing efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Advertising and Perceptions</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/07/2010-07-07-advertising-and-perc/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-07T08:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-07-07T08:40:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-07-07:/posts/2010/07/2010-07-07-advertising-and-perc/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-07-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-07-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road side stall, in the middle of banana fields, selling: bananas.  You think the bananas are from the local fields? Nope. I, and I wasn't alone, was thinking they where, but I arrived early one morning and met the guy restocking. Not so local bananas after all. He has a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-07-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-07-07-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road side stall, in the middle of banana fields, selling: bananas.  You think the bananas are from the local fields? Nope. I, and I wasn't alone, was thinking they where, but I arrived early one morning and met the guy restocking. Not so local bananas after all. He has a route restocking several road side stalls each day. Ripened bananas from the store room. I recall that he said the bananas did come from somewhere in the Far North Queensland area, but not the near by fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, your getting better value than the large supermarket stalls. I wonder how it pays though; The bananas sell at $2/kg. He has to buy them from a farmer, pay transport to get them to the store room, the store room running costs, costs of driving around stocking the stalls. How does this work to be economical to sell for $2/kg?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bicycle shorts: I don't use padded shorts, but the el cheapo KMart 'cycle shorts' also called gym wear. Recently was forced to actually buy a new pair, rather than finding a second hand pair. Lots of stickers on the product: "Moisture wicking fabric". Cynical me, checked the labels of the new versus the old; both the same  95% cotton, 5% elastane. Marketing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Wheel returns</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/07/2010-07-24-wheel-returns/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-24T21:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-07-24T21:38:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-07-24:/posts/2010/07/2010-07-24-wheel-returns/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100724.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100724.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wheel arrived back yesterday. Wow. It took 2 weeks to get to Rohloff. One day for Rohloff to do their magic, and 4 days to return. (I can't figure out how Australia Post works.)  I didn't waste any time putting it on and going for a spin. With 75kg load …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100724.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/20100724.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wheel arrived back yesterday. Wow. It took 2 weeks to get to Rohloff. One day for Rohloff to do their magic, and 4 days to return. (I can't figure out how Australia Post works.)  I didn't waste any time putting it on and going for a spin. With 75kg load - no problems. Didn't have a 120kg load handy to try with that, but I'm confident that its sorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to hang for a few more days. Promised to fix a laptop and am now waiting on a hard disk to arrive. It should arrive Monday (fingers crossed) so that I can leave here by the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>On the road again</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-03-on-the-road-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-03T16:57:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-03T16:57:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-03:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-03-on-the-road-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm off. At Rollingstone now. Going fishing tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding after so long an absence was tough. Way out of condition. Lots of sore spots right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GoGetter bags are to big i think for touring. Too much stuff in them. To hard to handle when full. And there is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm off. At Rollingstone now. Going fishing tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riding after so long an absence was tough. Way out of condition. Lots of sore spots right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GoGetter bags are to big i think for touring. Too much stuff in them. To hard to handle when full. And there is the temptation to fill them. Will give it longer while i think what to do about them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>beach bum</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-07-beach-bum/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-07T07:10:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-07T07:10:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-07:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-07-beach-bum/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07082010-745776.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07082010-745776.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hanging out at the beach right now. Its nice here. But to many people. You don't get to sleep to the sound of waves. But to the roar of generators and tv's. All the caravan crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoping to move on soon to somewhere more peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On fishing- i felt sorry …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07082010-745776.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07082010-745776.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hanging out at the beach right now. Its nice here. But to many people. You don't get to sleep to the sound of waves. But to the roar of generators and tv's. All the caravan crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoping to move on soon to somewhere more peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On fishing- i felt sorry for the live bait and was letting it go. Stopped fishing after that. Tried to talk some of the other people into letting their live bait go without success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll eat beans.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Prospecting</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-13-prospecting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-13T06:45:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-13T06:45:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-13:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-13-prospecting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm prospecting from a top secret location, along with dozens of other people. Can't say its that remote, what with mobile coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prospecting is a lot like fishing. Lots of time in the sun. Nothing happening pretty much most of the time. Rare bursts of excitement. Its also like looking …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm prospecting from a top secret location, along with dozens of other people. Can't say its that remote, what with mobile coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prospecting is a lot like fishing. Lots of time in the sun. Nothing happening pretty much most of the time. Rare bursts of excitement. Its also like looking for a needle in a hay stack. Looking for tiny bits of glass like rock, amongst other rocks and broken glass. Yeah, there's a fair bit of broken glass out here of the beer bottle type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found a couple of small stones though. To small for anything except to say I found them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately even out here there are generators running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are camped on the hill tops so the noise carriers. Being no a hill top also lets you find your camp again. Lots of gullies to go prospecting in. You can wander a fair way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that is missing out here is water. We had to carry all our water in. So our stay is limited to when that runs out. Probably this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>End of prospecting</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-18-end-of-prospecting/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-18T08:24:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-18T08:24:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-18:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-18-end-of-prospecting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image2.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that's over. Time to start pedalling again. Here are some shots from camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was interesting. Not sure if i'll do it again. Its hard work. Either walking bent over to see the stones or digging and washing dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end its all just colored glass to me …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image2.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-18-image2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that's over. Time to start pedalling again. Here are some shots from camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was interesting. Not sure if i'll do it again. Its hard work. Either walking bent over to see the stones or digging and washing dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end its all just colored glass to me. Bits of rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't cull stuff yet, so have a big load still.:(&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Alpha</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-18-alpha/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-18T09:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-18T09:30:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-18:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-18-alpha/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/18082010-748446.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/18082010-748446.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/17082010-749680.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/17082010-749680.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly lots of hills out here. Also lots of grey nomads. Some take there whole house with them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have ditched about 10kg of stuff and the bike is noticeably lighter now. Still more that can go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some grub has chewed holes in my tent! Hope it got a belly ache …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/18082010-748446.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/18082010-748446.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/17082010-749680.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/17082010-749680.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly lots of hills out here. Also lots of grey nomads. Some take there whole house with them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have ditched about 10kg of stuff and the bike is noticeably lighter now. Still more that can go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some grub has chewed holes in my tent! Hope it got a belly ache! Need to patch them as rain is forecast.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Alpha and onwards</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-19-alpha-and-onwards/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-19T09:28:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-19T09:28:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-19:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-19-alpha-and-onwards/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha caravan park wanted $20 for a tent site a night. Bugger that. Instead i ate up. Rested in the park. Chatted with some locals and tourists and then pedalled onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snows bakery really bakes! So yummy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road is very straight. 2.5 hours of slow, into the wind …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-19-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alpha caravan park wanted $20 for a tent site a night. Bugger that. Instead i ate up. Rested in the park. Chatted with some locals and tourists and then pedalled onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snows bakery really bakes! So yummy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road is very straight. 2.5 hours of slow, into the wind, gradual climbing.  Who said out here was flat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke about midnight. Thought i heard an elephant.the park at Alpha had a sign saying no camels or elephants. I know there are feral camels, but elephants? Whats and elephant sound like. At night, in a tent in the middle of nowhere it sounded like one to me. A few sleepless hours wondering, before i drifted off into sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lady at the shop in Jericho said it was likely a bull or deer. There aren't any elephants loose that she knows of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jericho is nice. Small and friendly. Going to stay here a few days for the rain to pass. And do voting here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Rest time</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-19-rest-time/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-19T17:17:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-19T17:17:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-19:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-19-rest-time/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/19082010-781337.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/19082010-781337.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My home for the next few days in Jericho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-08-19 22:36&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: a.k&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi! How are u DESUKA? Your home front of river seems cool NE! I love been near river YO! And I can see your black socks.... OMG (-.-)/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Sand surfing to Blackall</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-23-sand-surfing-to-blac/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-23T18:17:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-23T18:17:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-23:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-23-sand-surfing-to-blac/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got the itch Sunday lunchtime and decided to move on. After wavering a bit, i took the back road which ended up having about 60km of sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some times were good. Cruising along on the edge of a sand ridge, sliding down slightly cushioning out the corrugations. Grab to much …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got the itch Sunday lunchtime and decided to move on. After wavering a bit, i took the back road which ended up having about 60km of sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some times were good. Cruising along on the edge of a sand ridge, sliding down slightly cushioning out the corrugations. Grab to much sand though, and its wipe out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly it was hard work. Walking, pulling and pushing the bike along. I was glad when the sand stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some hard clay bits. A worry if it rained. Lucky it didn't. But the thought did keep me awake. Well the roaring wind probably did more. I'd camped in a ditch- that helped lessen the wind on the tent, but not the spot to be if it rains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-08-23-sand-surfing-to-blac.mp4" download&gt;
Here is a short video looking around when i got on the tar again.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Mud in Isisford</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-26-mud-in-isisford/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-26T06:59:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-26T06:59:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-26:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-26-mud-in-isisford/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Made Isisford yesterday morning. The road here seems to be uphill all the way! I might even go back to Blackall just for the downhill coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mail only comes here 3 times a week. The place is almost a ghost town, except for the grey nomads. $2 a night, $10 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Made Isisford yesterday morning. The road here seems to be uphill all the way! I might even go back to Blackall just for the downhill coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mail only comes here 3 times a week. The place is almost a ghost town, except for the grey nomads. $2 a night, $10 a week camping with a hot shower. I'm told some stay so long, they grow gardens. Cause when the heat arrives they all leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was cold yesterday. I had to set up tent and get in to warm up. Then it started raining. A very reluctant post of rain. Not alot, but enough to dampen everything. When i left the tent, i made my introduction to the local mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've known chewing gum that sticks less! I get 2 inch platform thongs walking ten meters. Thong straps are straining. Crickey. Haven't tried to ride in this. Going to stay here the week and hope it dries up. Birdsville track is closed- to much rain. So that rules that out for now. Need to see where next.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Another lazy weekend.:)</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/08/2010-08-30-another-lazy-weekend/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-30T06:42:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-08-30T06:42:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-08-30:/posts/2010/08/2010-08-30-another-lazy-weekend/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lazyed about and read. Watched people leave and grumped at some that come close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will leave tomorrow or wed. And go to Stonehenge. Will be 100km of dirt. Been culling weight. More stuff chucked out. Still lots to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So do you have a route from Dalby to Brisbane?end …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lazyed about and read. Watched people leave and grumped at some that come close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will leave tomorrow or wed. And go to Stonehenge. Will be 100km of dirt. Been culling weight. More stuff chucked out. Still lots to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So do you have a route from Dalby to Brisbane?end of october, i was thinking of being further south. Will be warning up by then...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megan  Xx &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Isisford</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/09/2010-09-03-isisford/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-03T10:05:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-09-03T10:05:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-09-03:/posts/2010/09/2010-09-03-isisford/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well time to move on. It has been really nice in Isisford. Wonderful people living there and travelling through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dirt road out of Isisford to Stonehenge was easy enough going. There is a lack of trees though when your at the Stonehenge end of the road. Lots of traffic …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image0.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image0.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image1.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/2010-09-03-image1.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well time to move on. It has been really nice in Isisford. Wonderful people living there and travelling through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dirt road out of Isisford to Stonehenge was easy enough going. There is a lack of trees though when your at the Stonehenge end of the road. Lots of traffic at the moment on the way to Birdsville for the races this weekend. Rain is forcaste so that could make it interesting for them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>New wheels!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/09/2010-09-07-new-wheels/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-07T21:44:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-09-07T21:44:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-09-07:/posts/2010/09/2010-09-07-new-wheels/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07092010020-701438.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07092010020-701438.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeap. Thats my current wheels.How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While sheltering from the wind and rain in the shade of a toilet block i noticed my rear rim had cracks! Lots in fact. Needless to say, i couldn't pedal on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to get both rims rebuilt on wider and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07092010020-701438.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07092010020-701438.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeap. Thats my current wheels.How did that happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While sheltering from the wind and rain in the shade of a toilet block i noticed my rear rim had cracks! Lots in fact. Needless to say, i couldn't pedal on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to get both rims rebuilt on wider and stronger rims. That will take some time, as i'm in the country. (There is a mail truck twice a week.) Until that is done, i've got a job: truck driving. I'm getting to see the road from up high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its an old truck. Patience with the gear changing is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm moving sand at the moment; Drive to point A. The truck is loaded. Drive to point B and empty it out. Go back to point A and repeat. Interestingly i'm finding it peaceful work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also been helping out with the usual computer problems, but truck driving is different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's stopped raining for now, and the temp is rising. Soon it will be "hot". Truck air-con is "keep the window open"&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Windorah!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/09/2010-09-10-windorah/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-10T21:32:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-09-10T21:32:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-09-10:/posts/2010/09/2010-09-10-windorah/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;More new jobs. Got to drive a bobcat for two days. Just like a playstation one guy said. Well i've never had a playstation, but the bobact was fun. Very intuitive controls; two joy sticks. Actually, its really called a front skid loader, but everyone knows the one brand: Bobcat …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;More new jobs. Got to drive a bobcat for two days. Just like a playstation one guy said. Well i've never had a playstation, but the bobact was fun. Very intuitive controls; two joy sticks. Actually, its really called a front skid loader, but everyone knows the one brand: Bobcat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was a trip to Windorah. I became a liquid waste management expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, i drove a truck. Known as the "poop truck".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeap, i pumped shit. Tanks in the ground fill up, someone (me today) drives up in a truck with a large tank, and a pump.  Put hose from pump into the tank, and pump until truck tank is full. Drive to a remote dump point and open value to empty truck tank. Avoid all contact with liquids, and stay upwind. Repeat until ground tank is empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its a smelly job, but someone has to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Go-Getters and rain</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/09/2010-09-12-gogetters-and-rain/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-12T21:46:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-09-12T21:46:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-09-12:/posts/2010/09/2010-09-12-gogetters-and-rain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010025-705106.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010025-705106.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010026-706415.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010026-706415.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning to comment on  using the Go-Getters for touring for a while now. Time to do it. They are huge! But, i think that they are not the best for touring.  This is my experience so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are not 100% water and dust proof. The lid folds …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010025-705106.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010025-705106.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010026-706415.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12092010026-706415.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning to comment on  using the Go-Getters for touring for a while now. Time to do it. They are huge! But, i think that they are not the best for touring.  This is my experience so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are not 100% water and dust proof. The lid folds over the bag opening. I've not been able to get it to a state that i'm happy with in dusty conditions, or that i'd trust it in driving rain. In rain i'm having important stuff in plastic bags. This is annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dust sticks in the weave of the fabric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think they might be mean't to be used with running boards and side boards. I'm not using either, and have found that the braze- on points, with button bolts in them are wearing the bags out. See the holes in the bottom of one bag in the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clips are not easy to operate, if your taking the bags on and off daily. I have ended up using two hold points on each bag-the inside two. The outside two are used to attach the shoulder strap. The shoulder strap makes picking up loaded bags easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that i cannot stuff goods into them in the same way as using roll top bags. If i stuff them too hard, the lid has a larger gap which has me worried for water and dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My bags sit on the wide loader, which is lower than the wheel axle. This is good for center of gravity, but the down side is that i've scrapped the bags on rocks, stumps, and road kill. They now have tiny holes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bags are weighty on their own. This is more in comparison to roll top bags. The fabric is thick and should last ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both shoulder straps broke the adjustment bit of plastic. Since this is one attachment point, both are now tied onto the bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be getting some roll top plastic bags. Ortlieb make some. I'm considering removing the wide loaders, and attaching some core flute on the sides of the rack. The two bags will them be hung in a cloth sling on the side. This will place them above the axle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll have to visit a larger town when mobile again to get the cloth, well probably canvas. I'll have a photo then. It may be easier to understand then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-09-18 06:39&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm waiting eagerly to see what kind of inventive suspension systems you will make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kai from Finland&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-09-18 20:29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'll be similar to the Xtracycle cargo bag- the Freeloader but made from canvas..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll not see that for several weeks yet. I'm estimating 3 weeks until my wheels are back. Then another week to get to a large town and buy stuff.I'm currently a long way from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Stranded in a one pub town.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Rain and cleaning</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/09/2010-09-28-rain-and-cleaning/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-28T21:21:00+10:00</published><updated>2010-09-28T21:21:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-09-28:/posts/2010/09/2010-09-28-rain-and-cleaning/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/23092010032-728668.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/23092010032-728668.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/27092010033-729695.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/27092010033-729695.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28092010034-730315.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28092010034-730315.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been raining a fair bit out here. Most unusual for September. The weir is flowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I using the mop each day. Cleaning the pub. My favourite kitchen appliance is the dishwasher! Load, press the button. 2 hours latter unpack hot dry everything! If i can fit it in, it's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/23092010032-728668.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/23092010032-728668.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/27092010033-729695.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/27092010033-729695.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28092010034-730315.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28092010034-730315.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been raining a fair bit out here. Most unusual for September. The weir is flowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I using the mop each day. Cleaning the pub. My favourite kitchen appliance is the dishwasher! Load, press the button. 2 hours latter unpack hot dry everything! If i can fit it in, it's going to washed by the machine. Still there are lots that don't fit. So hot water, soap, rubber gloves and scrub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh for my wheels...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Stonehenge, Isisford, Blackall</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/10/2010-10-07-stonehenge-isisford-/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-07T07:19:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-10-07T07:19:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-10-07:/posts/2010/10/2010-10-07-stonehenge-isisford-/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/01102010037-715431.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/01102010037-715431.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04102010040-716449.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04102010040-716449.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last day doing things in Stonehenge. Was helping cut the law on the ride on. Never used one before. I managed to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the bottomless pit (in fairness it wasn't marked, and was hidden in the knee high grass)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut the water pipe (plastic also hidden)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am now in Blackall …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/01102010037-715431.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/01102010037-715431.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04102010040-716449.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/04102010040-716449.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last day doing things in Stonehenge. Was helping cut the law on the ride on. Never used one before. I managed to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the bottomless pit (in fairness it wasn't marked, and was hidden in the knee high grass)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut the water pipe (plastic also hidden)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am now in Blackall. Was a long hot ride from Stonehenge to Isisford. Rolled in on 7pm after leaving at 4am. There was stops during the hot part of the day, and lots of rest stops after that. Slept several times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isisford the river was over the bridge. Walked that pushing the bike. Lots of mossies and sandflies about right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still having lots of hassles with bags. My blue waterproof bags are that, but getting them on the bike hasn't been as successful as i'd thought it would be. Thinking now that panniers, the tried and tested touring gear carriers are the go. My gear at the moment is held on with lots of straps and ocky straps. Looks big and messy, and is a pain to get on and off the bike and to find anything. Am sitting the blue bags in the yellow Go Getters. It the blue bags are upright, they tend to fall outwards. Lie them down and opening them without unpacking is hard. Tried putting different amounts of gear in them, and in the Go Getters. Haven't found a combination that works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fatter tires are way better. They provide some suspension, and track better on the dirt roads.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Jondaryan</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/10/2010-10-12-jondaryan/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-12T07:09:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-10-12T07:09:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-10-12:/posts/2010/10/2010-10-12-jondaryan/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12102010043-765772.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/12102010043-765772.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wet and cool is how things are now. Decided to escape the 36C temps out west and get closer to the coast. Funny how now a bit of that sun would be nice to dry everything out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Gold Coast</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/10/2010-10-24-gold-coast/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-24T15:56:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-10-24T15:56:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-10-24:/posts/2010/10/2010-10-24-gold-coast/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hanging out with friends on the Gold Coast now. Been very surprised about the cycle paths about Brisbane. They have much better facilaties than Sydney. Good paths that go everywhere I wanted to go. Clear signage. Maps. So awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ditching the GoGetters for panniers. About 7kg weight there. Wow. Also …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hanging out with friends on the Gold Coast now. Been very surprised about the cycle paths about Brisbane. They have much better facilaties than Sydney. Good paths that go everywhere I wanted to go. Clear signage. Maps. So awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ditching the GoGetters for panniers. About 7kg weight there. Wow. Also loosing the wide loader bar. Caught my foot on it a couple of times on rough roads. The panniers hang higher, which is a bonus:better ground clearance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Brisbane</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/11/2010-11-16-brisbane/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-16T12:21:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-11-16T12:21:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-11-16:/posts/2010/11/2010-11-16-brisbane/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07112010051-728325.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07112010051-728325.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still hanging out in Brisbane. Been doing some house painting- and old Queenslander. Also been waiting on a toy; a folding wireless keyboard. Lets me type blog updates on a real keyboard, rather than thumb typing on the phone. Still a small bit of painting to finish then I'm out …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07112010051-728325.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/07112010051-728325.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still hanging out in Brisbane. Been doing some house painting- and old Queenslander. Also been waiting on a toy; a folding wireless keyboard. Lets me type blog updates on a real keyboard, rather than thumb typing on the phone. Still a small bit of painting to finish then I'm out of here and heading south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-11-16 13:26&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool painting NE! and would like to see your new keyboard! atsu-chan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Back on the Road Again - Rosevale</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/11/2010-11-29-back-on-the-road-aga/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-29T06:54:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-11-29T06:54:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-11-29:/posts/2010/11/2010-11-29-back-on-the-road-aga/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010060-747571.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010060-747571.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010066-748893.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010066-748893.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010068-757247.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010068-757247.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010072-758203.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010072-758203.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010073-759348.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010073-759348.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left Brisbane at 5:39am - the first train out. I had intented to use the Google maps directions for walking to leave Rosewood Station, but the paths and sometimes roads where not there. Ended up going down roads that turned into dead ends. Some had fences across them - suggesting that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010060-747571.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010060-747571.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010066-748893.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010066-748893.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010068-757247.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010068-757247.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010072-758203.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/28112010072-758203.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010073-759348.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010073-759348.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left Brisbane at 5:39am - the first train out. I had intented to use the Google maps directions for walking to leave Rosewood Station, but the paths and sometimes roads where not there. Ended up going down roads that turned into dead ends. Some had fences across them - suggesting that they might have been open once..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was good being out in the country smells again - grass, gums, and cows. No road kill yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checked out all the cemetarys I passed. Lots of dead people, passed awy, some are resting, others were "called" (Why do they answer?), some "gone to a better place" (What didn't they like about this one?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was overcast, and warm. Spent three hours eating lunch and reading. Then started being more serious about getting somewhere. With a full stomach, it was slow pedalling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopped for a drink at a fence gate, and one of the few cars I'd seen stopped. They owned the paddock and were going to do some fencing. We talked for a couple minutes. They offered that I could sleep on their property. So I cycled in after them and helped them with the fencing. As we were moving along the fence, I found the best spot to camp. Little stream trickeling in the background, lots of birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woke up this morning to birds singing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictures; Tried different packing strategies. The great outdoors!! A model of a church that once existed in the cemetry. (Wonder if the church had problems with snakes?) The morning tent view &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2010-11-30 11:21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, Megan-SAN,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering how you are doing after that YO!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GENKI NE! Good!!! a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Texas</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-07-texas/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-07T18:38:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-07T18:38:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-12-07:/posts/2010/12/2010-12-07-texas/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010074-747990.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010074-747990.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010076-749391.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010076-749391.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/02122010078-752159.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/02122010078-752159.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a week it has been..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped a couple of days outside of Aratula. The second hand shop there, the guy gave me a book, so  I had to stick around to read and and drop it back. While there, I saw a koala in the wild!!!! The koala …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010074-747990.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010074-747990.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010076-749391.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/29112010076-749391.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/02122010078-752159.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/02122010078-752159.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a week it has been..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped a couple of days outside of Aratula. The second hand shop there, the guy gave me a book, so  I had to stick around to read and and drop it back. While there, I saw a koala in the wild!!!! The koala climed down one tree, ran across the ground and up another tree. Did this a few times before finding a tree it was happy with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After leaving, it was a two day climb up over the range. The road I picked had signs saying no trucks, semi trailers, caravans or busses. Some of the grades were 17%. Needless to say I walked lots of it. It would have had great views, but mostly I was struggling to see more than 20meters - fog or mist or clouds. It was cold and wet, wet, wet.  It took two days to climb the range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopped in Legume, and Liston for a night each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm currently in Texas staying in the caravan park.  Yes. There is a town called Texas in Qld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memorable moments;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a tree falls in the bush does it make a sound? You bet. At 9:15ish at night, I went from sleeping to crouched ready to run in one heatbeat. A very loud "crack", followed by the sound of  falling. In the morning i found some small twigs had hit the tent. The dead tree fell towards the tent, but the top of the branches stopped about 10meters away..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digging a hole in the rain forest is hard work - lots of roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Killarney to the NSW border, the road is called "Border Road". at the border, in NSW the road is called Killarney Road. QLD likes having the roads called Border road. Same thing happened when crossing again on the way to Stanthorpe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texas has sheep farming- lots of flies. Dig any hole early in the morning before the flies wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New top speed - 79.5km/hr. Might have been faster but i put the brakes on early on.. But then lost a water bottle the speed crept up before I knew it..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rain stings over 50kn/hr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being wet each day has its problems. I wear the same clothes each day. I've only three sets: one to wear, one to sleep or change into and one spare. So if one pair is wet, and its still raining, they go back on the next day. I found that I have lots of little blisters or boils. Any small cut would easily become infected.  A day of being dry has helped them a lot. Clothes that are wet constantly smell. In short before washing today - I stunk.  Going past road kill, the flies would all leave to follow me. I had so many on me, I'd chase them off to make the uphills easier.  Fair dinkum!!!  Skin softens in the water, and I found small pills of skin in the tent. Any callouses I had are long gone.. But after all of it, one good wash and everything is gone. I smell clean again, my clothes have the soap and sun dried smell. Looking foward to sleeping tonight - a clean dry bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blue Ortlieb bags have shown a problem. The top is closed by a roll down, but the edge has a cloth strip. This strip soaks up the water and lets a few drops inside. I'm going to spray silicon on it when I get some to stop that. For the moment I'm double bagging to stop my sleeping bag getting damp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panniers on the Yuba Mundo work well. I feel like I can ride faster than with thee Go-Getters. Its also easier to pack and unpack the bike. Its also easier to push the bike up hill - the wide loader bar isn't in the way. The panniers sit a few inches higher  - which is a big help when crossing water. I walked through water up to just below the axle height. The go-Getters would have been in the water, and lifting the bike. Water that deep has a lot of force. I wouldn't like to walk through any deeper flowing water...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road side heading away from my cow paddock camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;second hand shop at Aratula&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;koala in a tree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture taking has been limited in the wet. My phone isn't water proof, and mostly I was so wet, I didn't want to risk opening the water proof bag to get out the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all the rain - it isn't as unpleasent as you might think. It does make for some changes, like stopping earlier to give the inside of the tent time to dry, or taking longer to setup and take down the tent.. And when the sun comes out its so magical.  Riding in the rain is easier in some ways - its cooler, and there isn't any water shortages :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2014-06-29 08:09&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: TimM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megan, I'm loving your blog!  TTT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Inveral</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-13-inveral/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-13T10:58:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-13T10:58:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-12-13:/posts/2010/12/2010-12-13-inveral/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had enough resting in Texas. The weather had returned to showers, so time to move on. Left Sunday morning in the rain. Later in the day the sun came out and it was hot. Tar melting hot. Tar was running like honey in some spots.  Rested in Ashford for a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had enough resting in Texas. The weather had returned to showers, so time to move on. Left Sunday morning in the rain. Later in the day the sun came out and it was hot. Tar melting hot. Tar was running like honey in some spots.  Rested in Ashford for a while- most of the mid day actually. Then stopped about 20km outside of Inveral for another few hours.. Slept beside a hay field. Oh did that smell nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More showers on the way..&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Barraba</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-20-barraba/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-20T16:09:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-20T16:09:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-12-20:/posts/2010/12/2010-12-20-barraba/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010081-718329.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010081-718329.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010080-719259.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010080-719259.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010085-719757.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010085-719757.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010089-720343.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010089-720343.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010090-721580.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010090-721580.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back in Barraba. But only for a short time. I was good resting here for a couple of days, but the weather is cool and sunny and I've itchy feet. Want to keep moving..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road here from Inverell was interesting. Met several wonderful people.  I'll have more on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010081-718329.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010081-718329.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010080-719259.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010080-719259.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010085-719757.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/14122010085-719757.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010089-720343.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010089-720343.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010090-721580.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/15122010090-721580.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back in Barraba. But only for a short time. I was good resting here for a couple of days, but the weather is cool and sunny and I've itchy feet. Want to keep moving..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road here from Inverell was interesting. Met several wonderful people.  I'll have more on that in the new year. Emails are being exchanged, plans are being formed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stopped at Copeland Dam briefly. The water level was down to 6%, its now at 40%. Long way till the spill ways are in use again.  The road travels along the top of the dam wall. You can see the two different height trees - the old growth, and the new trees growing on land that should be under water when the dam is full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the road was dirt - hilly and steep, meandering amongst the cows. I crossed several causeways, flowing with water high enought to get wet feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the rain, there are lots of flies, and mossies. The flies are the ones that try and go up your nose, and into your eyes. Don't open your mouth!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The land is very green and lush. On one steep hill, I got to see two Dung Bettles rolling a ball of dung along. They were much smaller than I expected, but very entertaining. I just wish it wasn't on such a steep hill.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Boggabri, Mullaley</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-23-boggabri-mullaley/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-23T13:55:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-23T13:55:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-12-23:/posts/2010/12/2010-12-23-boggabri-mullaley/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010092-746579.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010092-746579.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010094-748678.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010094-748678.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictures: Wean race course. Its overgrown with grass at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the rock pools at Dripping Rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn't leave Barraba until 11:30. A very late start for me. Lucky 10km down the road was a shed. Rested there and had lunch till the sun cooled off a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010092-746579.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010092-746579.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010094-748678.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/22122010094-748678.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictures: Wean race course. Its overgrown with grass at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the rock pools at Dripping Rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn't leave Barraba until 11:30. A very late start for me. Lucky 10km down the road was a shed. Rested there and had lunch till the sun cooled off a bit.  Lots of dirt roads, flies, mossies and cows. Very quiet on the road though.  Sorted out the flies. I've some strings hanging off my helment, that swing in front of my face. Keeps the flies out of my eyes and nose.  Took a detour to see "Dripping Rock". Yep, its a waterfall, that was flowing. Been a lot of rain lately here. My plans to have a swim were dashed but the number of mossies. Some are basically flying syringes. Standing still - you could almost feel your blood pressure dropping. No chance I going to give them more skin to feast on.  Had a flat tire this morning. It went down yesterday, but after pumping it up, I kept riding for another 40km to find a spot to camp. With all the rain here, there is a lot of water lying around on the road side. Got wet feet several times going over causeways.  Flat repair was easy, once I moved into the tent to do it. To many mossies outside. The hole looks like a thorn - but couldn't find anything stuck in the tire. Time will tell if I missed it. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Tambar Springs, Coolah and beyond the Black Stump</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-25-tambar-springs-coola/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-25T06:02:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-25T06:02:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-12-25:/posts/2010/12/2010-12-25-tambar-springs-coola/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010100-750600.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010100-750600.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010101-751564.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010101-751564.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010102-752378.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010102-752378.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tambarr Springs has amazing views out across the  landscape. But I didn't see any unusual creatures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found a small cemetry tucked away in the bushes on the edge of the road between Tambar Springs and Coolah. I wonder how many people notice it. Most of the stones are unreadable, but …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010100-750600.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010100-750600.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010101-751564.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010101-751564.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010102-752378.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2010/24122010102-752378.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tambarr Springs has amazing views out across the  landscape. But I didn't see any unusual creatures...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found a small cemetry tucked away in the bushes on the edge of the road between Tambar Springs and Coolah. I wonder how many people notice it. Most of the stones are unreadable, but saw 1800's mentioned more than once.. A few more years and nothing will be left.. The last deposit was in 1993.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Black Stump! I've passed it. I'm beyond the black stump. The pic is from on side. Not sure if before or after it. It looks like a burn't branch to me actually. A plaque states there was a black stump once, but was burned down in a fire. A long with the hotel that was near by..   The black stump isn't what it once was... The silly season is in full swing, and its now a rest stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decided to stop in Coolah, as the roads are crazy busy. And for a small back road, just too many idiot about..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be moans about the road toll over Xmass/New Year. The thing I find surprising is that there are not more crashes. Slowing up is a fate worse than death..&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Ulan, Bylong</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-27-ulan-bylong/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-27T06:15:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-27T06:15:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-12-27:/posts/2010/12/2010-12-27-ulan-bylong/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Christmass day:birds singing, water rushing. Memories of childhood christmass days. Food, rest. Watched the couple near by move their baby about all day - to get it into the shade, closer to where they had moved their chairs. Designer baby. Straight from Toyota land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a sudden heavy down …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Christmass day:birds singing, water rushing. Memories of childhood christmass days. Food, rest. Watched the couple near by move their baby about all day - to get it into the shade, closer to where they had moved their chairs. Designer baby. Straight from Toyota land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a sudden heavy down pour, but then it fined up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set off early on Boxing day with overcaste weather. Planned to stop in Ulan. Hit a new Top Speed: 81.86km/hr. Down hill obviously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulan has lots of mines. Air smelt of sulphur.  Was raining heavy when I got near there. Decided to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More driver silliness: Saw a car pulled over - but disappointingly saw that they stopped to add more rum to their drink.  A 4wd packed with young males, speeding along a rough dirt road. Bouncing, slipping or skidding, airborne, stones and water flying out the sides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with all my gear on the back, the back wheel can lose traction on wet clay. Most unsettling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;125km for the day. 8hours pedalling time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Muswellbrook</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2010/12/2010-12-30-muswellbrook/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-30T18:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-30T18:00:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2010-12-30:/posts/2010/12/2010-12-30-muswellbrook/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Left Bylong early on a cloudy day and was riding to Jerry Plains. But on the way I met Graham from
&lt;a href="http://www.jamesestatewines.com.au/"&gt;James Estate Wines&lt;/a&gt;
out for a ride. We rode along and chatted. Graham also rides mountain bikes. He suggested I stop in and say Hi to Jan, as their …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Left Bylong early on a cloudy day and was riding to Jerry Plains. But on the way I met Graham from
&lt;a href="http://www.jamesestatewines.com.au/"&gt;James Estate Wines&lt;/a&gt;
out for a ride. We rode along and chatted. Graham also rides mountain bikes. He suggested I stop in and say Hi to Jan, as their cellar was open that day. Glad I did. I met up with Jan when I was in Stonehenge. She was on a bus going to the Birdsville Races. She didn't get to Birdsville, because of the rain, but I didn't know that.. Stayed and chatted for some time. Ended up leaving with a bottle of Verdelho. (Had some last night - it was good. Everyone liked it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further down the road I found I missed the turn off I wanted to take. The Golden Highway was busy, with no shoulder at all. After half a km, I wasn't keen to keep going towards Jerry Plains, so turned back and ended up heading to Muswellbrook. Much more pleasant road to ride on. The only down side was the strong head wind all the way. It was a pedal down hill day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muswellbrook has City Rail trains to Sydney. But, only a few trains a day. I arrived at 4:30pm, the next train was at 9:00pm. From there to Hamilton to wait a hour for the next train towards Sydney at 11:37pm. Sydney City Rail service has a few weaknesses; no staff, no station announcements and no indicator boards. Past the time that the train was to arrive, a train arrived, and I foolishly got on it, only to find that I was heading back towards Muswellbrook. Bailed out at the next station, and rode back to Hamiltion Station. One of the first times I've used my mobile phone and Google Maps to navigate about in suburbia. The next Sydney train was at 2:38am, but it didn't arrive on time either. Arrived at Morisset Station close to 4am. Since I often wake about this time, and had had no sleep, I bunked down on the station bench until 6am for a short nap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently visiting friends at Morisset for a few days, before heading to Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Lithgow</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/01/2011-01-10-lithgow/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-10T19:17:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-01-10T19:17:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-01-10:/posts/2011/01/2011-01-10-lithgow/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well arrived in Sydney on the Monday, and then left to go camping up near Lithgow with Claire. We rode a track towards Newnes. Twas a nice track. Had to unpack the bikes and carry the gear and bikes past a few obstructions. Lucky for two of us - the Yuba …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well arrived in Sydney on the Monday, and then left to go camping up near Lithgow with Claire. We rode a track towards Newnes. Twas a nice track. Had to unpack the bikes and carry the gear and bikes past a few obstructions. Lucky for two of us - the Yuba is a bit heavy for me to lift on my own over some things - like fence gates. Also with two, we were able to lift the bikes over other obstructions without unpacking them.  For a four day trip, I had a lot of failures in the footwear departmeent - my Shimano sandals and thongs broke. Both held together by cable ties quite successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in Sydney - have started replacing or upgrading gear. Thermarest is in for a warrenty claim - its got a large bubble in the middle of it. Might go a lighter version or foam when or if it returns.  Need to patch holes in the tent. Replaced the crank puller with the way lighter Shimano version. 5mm thick steel  knife sharpener is being replaced with a 50gm version. Folding knife that doesn't lock shut is being replaced with one with a better lock so it stays shut when it should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aslo culling over weight items. 0.5kg of paper converted to pdf.  0.5kg bag of string chopped to just one piece for the clothes line. Clothes that are too worn but still carried are discard and replaced.  "spare" clothes that never been used  have been given away. Spare fuel bottle is gone. Keeping the 650ml bottle only.  Blue Ortlieb bags are gone - cut down enouth bulk to shove everything into the panniers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had 26kg when left Brisbane - thats before food and water and includes pannier weight. Will see what it all weighs when I leave Sydney next. Will be about for  couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2011-01-10 19:58&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey mate, looking forward to catching up while you're in Sydney. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Busking</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/01/2011-01-13-busking/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-13T05:19:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-01-13T05:19:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-01-13:/posts/2011/01/2011-01-13-busking/</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/09012011109-704990.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/09012011109-704990.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No not me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While wandering about Sydney, I stopped to listen to Alex and Mish playing and singing outside of Broadway Shopping Center. Great music.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Bye bye Yuba</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-bye-bye-yuba/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-25T12:08:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-01-25T12:08:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-01-25:/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-bye-bye-yuba/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Changing your bike again!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, been a few changes over the past year. Each time I thought it was the "right" decision. What can I say - I make some bad decisions.  But am learning :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Yuba definitely rides smoothly. Nice bike for cruising along. Also works well for carrying what …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Changing your bike again!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, been a few changes over the past year. Each time I thought it was the "right" decision. What can I say - I make some bad decisions.  But am learning :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Yuba definitely rides smoothly. Nice bike for cruising along. Also works well for carrying what ever you want. No worries about the strengh of the frame. Going to miss the solid no flex rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am currently back on my old Aluminium MTB frame. The Yuba is on ebay and has offers so it will sell. Why the change? Number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extra length touring causes me problems. About town I can't get into some lifts, going through bicycle path squeeze points - it doesn't make it. I have to lift the back wheel up and move it to make it around. This also happens on the wheel chair ramps. The weight of my gear and the bike and the length don't make it easy for me to do this. Not I'm not in town that much, but the lifting and moving it affects me even in the bush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can't lift it over a fence easily. Noticed this more on the Lithgow trip with a friend on a standard length bike. Two of us managed, but I wouldn't do it on my own. (Actually, I can't lift the Yuba easily even when unloaded.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've no hope of getting it on a plane because of the extra weight and the length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, the extra weight - noticing it more that I'm in Sydney. Places I've cycled lots. I expect to travel a certain speed and with the Yuba that isn't possible. Interestingly this didn't bother me in the country. So think its just I'm "back in the old places".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after anguishing over it for a few weeks, its back to the MTB frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/bike.jpg"  &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/bike.jpg"  /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;My old MTB without the wrapped frame.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Chain breaker on a diet</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-chain-breaker-on-a-d/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-25T12:31:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-01-25T12:31:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-01-25:/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-chain-breaker-on-a-d/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011117.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011117.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011119.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011119.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removing the handles saves 40gm. I use the shifter (adjustable spanner) on the body, and a 5mm allen key in on the screw drive. Also packs in my tool kit easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2014-11-27 15:34&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much does the shifter weigh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2014-11-27 15:40 …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011117.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011117.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011119.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011119.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removing the handles saves 40gm. I use the shifter (adjustable spanner) on the body, and a 5mm allen key in on the screw drive. Also packs in my tool kit easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2014-11-27 15:34&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much does the shifter weigh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2014-11-27 15:40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Lee Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't have a scale handy to weigh it. The previous one was 200gm. The new one, about 150gm I'm guessing.  I'm already carrying the shifter for other uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Webbing and Ocky straps</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-webbing-and-ocky-str/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-25T12:43:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-01-25T12:43:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-01-25:/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-webbing-and-ocky-str/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011120.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011120.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use two straps around my panniers to hold them in place.  The metal buckle is easy and quick to use, but weighs 56 grams.  Cut it off and use two cable ties like D-rings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also cut off the extra strap that is not needed. Too long is just a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011120.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011120.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use two straps around my panniers to hold them in place.  The metal buckle is easy and quick to use, but weighs 56 grams.  Cut it off and use two cable ties like D-rings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also cut off the extra strap that is not needed. Too long is just a hassle to keep out of the wheels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT: This doesn't work as well as I'd thought on the bike. IF you set it up and load the ends, it holds well, but pull the end to tighten the load and the cable ties roll, and then slip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3-May-2011: EDIT: On the road, still trying to use this method, I found that if I tighten the cable ties enough, so the strap has to fold to pass through it, then it works really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011121.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011121.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ocky straps have evil metal hooks on them. Evil because the little black rubber boots on the end of the wire soon comes off, then the wire hook punctures tents, panniers, and skin easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy shock cord from Bunnings and cheap clips from a $2 shop. Tie two knots to keep the cord from working lose. Shock cord is more elastic than the ocky straps, and you can make the cord exactly the length you need.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Exped Auriga Mesh Tent</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-exped-auriga-mesh-te/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-25T13:42:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-01-25T13:42:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-01-25:/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-exped-auriga-mesh-te/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Exped Auriga Tent  3100gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exped Auriga tent footprint 350gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheap Poly Blue 6x8 tarp 220gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheap Poly Green 6x8 tarp 340gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  blue tarp goes on the ground, then the footprint is placed on top of  that. The tent sits on the footprint. Some of my tent sites have lots …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Exped Auriga Tent  3100gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exped Auriga tent footprint 350gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheap Poly Blue 6x8 tarp 220gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheap Poly Green 6x8 tarp 340gm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  blue tarp goes on the ground, then the footprint is placed on top of  that. The tent sits on the footprint. Some of my tent sites have lots of  sharp stones. The blue tarp is getting very thin now and has many  holes. I'll replace it soon. The footprint also has holes. So far the tent bottom is not holed yet, but does have some thinner spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon after starting to use the tent I emailed Exped asking about UV resistance. The instructs say to "avoid prologed UV exposure". What is prolonged?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their reply was very fast: "When daily exposed to the sun the fly will have a live span of around half a year. The fabric than will be UV-damaged, easy to rip and dull color. To expand the span of life of your tent, pitch it up in a shady place take away the fly or cover the tent with a UV-proof foil, like a first aid sheet." I've followed this - covering the tent, moving it about in the shade, or even taking it down if staying somewhere for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tent has a 5 year warranty, and I had one claim on it leaking. Exped couldn't find where it was leaking, but seam sealed it again. They also said they were happy to look at the issue again if it leaked, and asked that I mark the leaking points. They also noted that they had not had problems before with leaking. I only found good reviews online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of months later it did leak again. I elected not to claim again, as I'd be without a tent for the time to send it to Sydney, get it tested, and returned. So I bought some seam sealer and covered the seams again. I also started using the green tarp to cover the top of the tent when it rains. Not sure if it is the seam sealer or the tarp on top, but I haven't had it leak since. And it has been in some very heavy rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be very sore on this tent considering the money I paid for it. But now after looking at other tents and having used it lots of different locations and circumstances, I'm feeling very friendly towards it. I appreciate more now the features and quality in the tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think my tent is "heavy" like I was initially. Consider this: the lighter weight tents are lighter because of thinner fabric. Thinner fabric isn't going to last as long, and is more prone to damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I don't like about this tent is the bag. You pack it in from the top like a shopping bag. There is no real closing for this - just a string across middle of the opening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I'm giving it a UV treatment and going to add patches to the thinner spots on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2017-12-29 16:24&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Thomas Venney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Electronics</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-electronics/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-25T16:15:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-01-25T16:15:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-01-25:/posts/2011/01/2011-01-25-electronics/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not carrying a laptop or netbook - not because I don't want one; just waiting for technology to catch up. I want a screen that is readable in the sunlight, better battery life and low power usage - then it can be charged either from the hub or solar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm not carrying a laptop or netbook - not because I don't want one; just waiting for technology to catch up. I want a screen that is readable in the sunlight, better battery life and low power usage - then it can be charged either from the hub or solar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present I'm using a Nokia 5800 as my main gadget. It works doing: gps, maps(on and off line), camera, web browser, email client,  ebook reader, mp3 player, radio, note taker,sms and lastly lets not forget, for phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So any photos are taken from the phone. Blog posts when not a PC are emailed though. Bit limited for the formating options, but one day I'll get a better phone, until then this is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;  
&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011124.jpg"  &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011124.jpg"  /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Solar charger. $1 AUD coin for scale.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To power this, I'm using a small solar panel  It is book sized, and  has two 6v 400mA panels that can be used individually, or joined for 12V  400mA. Love this. While there's sun, I've power. One day I will work at  connecting the Schmitt hub up to a battery pack to gather more energy  while riding. But for now, the sun is working fine for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to only put it out in the sun when I was stopped. Recently I've been ocky strapping it on top of the panniers. By keeping the phone in the pannier and rolling the top of the pannier losely, it keeps the phone out of the dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can also play music from the phone while its inside the panner. Was doing this with the music on the phone speaker, but could use ear phones if I wanted.  I don't bother playing music when riding. Only used it when walking when most of the day was pushing up hill. Singing along seemed to make the hills shorter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011125.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011125.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in Brisbane, I purchased this small folding blue tooth keyboard. Its wonderful. Really love being able to type normally. If you look back on my posts, before Brisbane, they tended to be very short. With this little baby, I can type longer posts. Great for emailing friends or taking notes. Takes one AAA battery, and so far its still on the same one. Smart circuits to shut things down when its not being used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011126.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img  src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/25012011126.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do have a battery pack (2000mAH USB connectors for charging from solar panel) than can charge the phone. But so far I haven't used it. I might not continue to carry this. It seemed like a good idea at the time, but practically, I use the phone most when its sunny, and when its raining, I don't get it out to avoid getting it wet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Surly Troll</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-05-surly-troll/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-05T09:53:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-05T09:53:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-05:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-05-surly-troll/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/05022011135-726668.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/05022011135-726668.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new love of my life. Lusted after a Surly 1x1 for years, but the new Troll is a way better watch for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picked her up yesterday afternoon. Twas a late night after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2011-02-19 03:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for posting the pic!  I'm putting together …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/05022011135-726668.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/05022011135-726668.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new love of my life. Lusted after a Surly 1x1 for years, but the new Troll is a way better watch for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picked her up yesterday afternoon. Twas a late night after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2011-02-19 03:28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for posting the pic!  I'm putting together a Troll build very similar to yours.  Would you mind giving details of your build?  I'm especially interested in your drive train choices and your fender and tire width.  I want to use a Tubus Cosmo rack, but I'm not sure if it will fit with my Big Apple 2.35" tires and SKS 65mm fenders. Thanks, Scott&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2011-02-23 10:23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll try to add more info for you. Let me know if you need anything more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2011-03-14 14:08&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Anonymous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice setup.  I'm curious, did you get the 16" or 18" frame?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Vincent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2014-08-04 20:53&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Ron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G'day Megan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham at Ridgways Cycles put me onto your blog. I'm going to follow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a ride on Route 66 in 2012 on a Surly Troll  I bought it in Chicago. If you want a read, the blog I wrote about the trip can be reached here http://www.crazyguyonabike.com/doc/rootedon66.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Troll is only the second new bike I've ever owned (the first was a Malvern Star tourer given to me in 1979) I still own both. I'm contemplating doing another long bike trip, but not sure when or where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy trails&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron Maskell, Brisbane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2014-08-05 18:56&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Lee Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Ron,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the link. I've since read about your trip. Amazing. Love the old photos you have. You put a lot of work into your trip journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep on cycling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Schwalbe Tires</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-07-schwalbe-tires/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-07T12:47:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-07T12:47:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-07:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-07-schwalbe-tires/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011140-780813.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011140-780813.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was talking with a future cycle tourer this morning, and we were going through bike bits. Whats good and what isn't.  He was tossing up what light weigh folding tire  to take as a spare for his year long trip. Luckily he had  already found the best brand:  Schwalbe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schwalbe …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011140-780813.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011140-780813.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was talking with a future cycle tourer this morning, and we were going through bike bits. Whats good and what isn't.  He was tossing up what light weigh folding tire  to take as a spare for his year long trip. Luckily he had  already found the best brand:  Schwalbe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schwalbe are the only tires I use. I came across them originally by chance, but now don't use anything else. Why? Simple. No flats. Well maybe not no flats ever, but darn close to that. Before Schwalbe tires, I was fast at fixing punctures. The quick stop, get tools, tire lever off the bit of tire where the puncture was, pull out the tube a bit, file tire, glue, press out the thorn/glass/nail from tire, patch on glue, press, push tire in tube, tire on rim, pump, tools back in the bag, wipe hands and cycle on.  I was fast from lots of practice with cheap tires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, after a bad run of flats, I asked my local bike shop if there were any better tires for punctures. Result was Schwalbe tires.  That was years ago when I was still riding to work.  I still fixed flats - on other peoples bikes. But commuting, I didn't have another puncture. And there were times when I rode over so much glass, that I was cringing just  waiting for the tire to deflate. It never did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now touring,  I've managed to puncture a couple of times. I like riding on dirt roads, and camping in the bush. Often I'll ride off the road, across the drain and into a paddock. Sometimes the tires are furry with thorns and prickles.  Maybe this got me once. Don't know.  I  had one puncture that I don't know the cause of late last year. I suspect barbed wire.  My other puncture was from running over a tent peg on the road.  It rattled around in the spokes and frame, and then jamed into the tire. Granted the tire was worn, and maybe should have been changed hundreds of km sooner, I don't think anything would have stood up to that tent peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently with over 7000km touring I'm very happy to be running Schwalbe tires. I like to spend my time riding,  not fixing flats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the light weight spare folding tire? What I do is just take another full tire. There isn't much weight savings on a folding tire. The folding tire isn't going to be the same as what your using each day. Even if you just use it to "get you to the nearest town" - the next town may not have the tire you want (or any tires!). So just carry a spare of what tire you use. And  of course, use  Schwalbe tires&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Rear view mirror</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-07-rear-view-mirror/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-07T13:01:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-07T13:01:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-07:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-07-rear-view-mirror/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011139-730378.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011139-730378.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think mirrors were not needed on bicycles. Shamefully, I used to heap scorn on anyone who suggested using a mirror. Why would you want a mirror when you can turn your head and see behind you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As so often is the case, after trying a mirror, I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011139-730378.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/07022011139-730378.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think mirrors were not needed on bicycles. Shamefully, I used to heap scorn on anyone who suggested using a mirror. Why would you want a mirror when you can turn your head and see behind you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As so often is the case, after trying a mirror, I now wouldn't be without one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mirror lets you see at a glance if there is anything coming behind. It doesn't replace turning your head and looking behind, but it sure does help let you know what is happening behind at times when you can't turn your head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure you can often hear there is a car or truck coming. But not always. Depending on the wind, you get no warning at all. Also, while you might hear the first car or truck, if there are several,  you will not be able to tell if there is one or more from the sound.  As the first is going past, and your concentrating on avoiding potholes, or rough edges, a quick glance in the mirror lets  you know how many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a handle bar mirror, rather than a helmet mounted one, cause I didn't like the way the helmet mounted mirrors create a blind spot. But other people swear that helmet ones are best.  What ever works for you - try them both.  Get a mirror and discover how useful it is in leting you know what is going on behind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Tooth Ache :(</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-08-tooth-ache/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-08T08:06:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-08T08:06:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-08:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-08-tooth-ache/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My planed date to leave Sydney is up in the air again. Saturday morning a tooth started aching. By Sunday it was clear that it wasn't going to get better on its own. Luckily yesterday I was able to see a dentist. Unfortunately, its not clear which of two teeth …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My planed date to leave Sydney is up in the air again. Saturday morning a tooth started aching. By Sunday it was clear that it wasn't going to get better on its own. Luckily yesterday I was able to see a dentist. Unfortunately, its not clear which of two teeth is the problem. One hurts on pressing, the other doesn't respond to hot/cold feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More pain and off to see a specialist today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a bright side to this? Maybe. Its probably better to have this happen in Sydney than out in the country where the dental services are fewer and further apart.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Tooth ache, Wheel bearings and Bicycle Computers</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-09-tooth-ache-wheel-bea/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-09T11:38:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-09T11:38:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-09:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-09-tooth-ache-wheel-bea/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011143-720115.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011143-720115.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tooth is still sore. Specialist thinks it might get better, or might not. But to come back in another month, unless it heals or hurts more. Arrrgggh... $220 for "extended consultation" (maybe 15 minutes all up), x-ray, and "Pulp vitality test" (Bite down on this - does that hurt?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011143-720115.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011143-720115.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tooth is still sore. Specialist thinks it might get better, or might not. But to come back in another month, unless it heals or hurts more. Arrrgggh... $220 for "extended consultation" (maybe 15 minutes all up), x-ray, and "Pulp vitality test" (Bite down on this - does that hurt?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it gets worse, it root canal treatment - that will be about $2000. Ouch. It it stops hurting, then all would be good for a while. Needless to say, I'm keen on it settling down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Front wheel bearings in the Schmitt hub are gone. Was trying to think how many km they have done, but apart from the 7000 odd touring, they did service for a couple of years before that, when I didn't have a bike computer.  To get them changed is going to take a week. A place down Melbourne does them. Luckily for me, I was loaned a spare front wheel that I can use to ride about on in the mean time. So getting the bearings changed now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dropped the bike computer and broke the button off. I can still change it with a small twig, and found the button. Going to try and glue it up,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else can fail/break?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been doing some more tidying up on the Troll. Yesterdays effort was a small guard to stop my heel swipping off the caliper bleed cover.  Next time I need  a new caliper, I'll look at where the bleeder exits. Not something you think of normally.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Lunch and more</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-09-lunch-and-more/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-09T20:33:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-09T20:33:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-09:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-09-lunch-and-more/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/09022011146-733394.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/09022011146-733394.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was heading back to where I'm staying, via some of the dumpsters I've visited in the past. Being away, places have shut down and of course new places have opened. Its not the best area, but sometimes you get lucky. Today was one of those days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ended up with  9 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/09022011146-733394.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/09022011146-733394.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was heading back to where I'm staying, via some of the dumpsters I've visited in the past. Being away, places have shut down and of course new places have opened. Its not the best area, but sometimes you get lucky. Today was one of those days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ended up with  9 loaves of bread, and some buns. Cause I wasn't going to eat that much so spent most of the afternoon finding people to give bread to.  Was looking for people begging, or in need. Some beggers didn't want food, only money.  Gave away all that I didn't want  in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn't actually looking for food though. Was looking for some stainless steel to make a bracket for my front rack. I'm going to mount a rear Tubus Cosmo rack on the front.  My plan needs a small U shaped bracket. I want this to be stainless steel.  Didn't find any this time. I did pick up a handful of milling and lathe bits from one skip outside a house in the suburbs. Going to find someone to give them to tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also gathered up some clothes and dropped them in to one of the church charity bins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling happy with the day. Nothing like digging around in bins, and giving stuff away.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Hebie Stabilizer</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-10-hebie-stabilizer/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-10T17:32:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-10T17:32:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-10:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-10-hebie-stabilizer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011145-767468.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011145-767468.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011147-768467.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011147-768467.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011148-769872.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011148-769872.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todays problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broken spoke on rear wheel. Not had this in years. Hoping it is just a weak spoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebie Stabilizer fell apart - well more so than it had before. There was a cosmetic bit of plastic tubing that covered the spring and attachment points - that fell off before the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011145-767468.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08022011145-767468.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011147-768467.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011147-768467.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011148-769872.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/10022011148-769872.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todays problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broken spoke on rear wheel. Not had this in years. Hoping it is just a weak spoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hebie Stabilizer fell apart - well more so than it had before. There was a cosmetic bit of plastic tubing that covered the spring and attachment points - that fell off before the first photo was taken. This time the spring fell off when the clamp became loose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stablizer keeps the front wheel pointing forward when you lean your bike against a post, or put the bike on a center stand.  For me, it also stops the front light I have mounted at the top of the fork, being bashed against the frame. I had one on the Yuba, till my spring broke. (I got a spring from the hardware store. Yuba sell a spring, that is probably way better suited than the one I used.) The Yuba has a drilled mounting point on the down tube.  The Hebie uses a "one size fits all" clamp. It was good while it worked. It looks like the strap that goes around the down tube slipped when the plastic coating softened. I know we have had some hot weather here lately, but was it that hot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I removed it as there didn't seem to be much point keeping it on. Looking at how the clamp works, I'm not impressed.  Its also marked the paint:(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time I wouldn't recommend buying a Hebie Stabilizer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later I found the spring! That was a bit of luck. So have it on with a cable tie for now. And I cable tied one end of the spring on so that it cannot fall off and get lost again. The cable tie will not be a long term solution. If I keep this, then I'll be looking for a better clamp. Means I'll be making my own up. If I do that, I'd go to all stainless steel or aluminium fittings so they don't rust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll wait until I have my front rack fitted, because then I'll be moving the light to another location. Stopping the light getting hit was my main reason for fitting the stabilizer. On the Yuba I had a piece of water pipe around the light to protect it.  The light is plastic - repeated hits on the frame would not be good for its long term health. I like my light, so am looking out for it. I keep a sock on it during the day to reduce UV exposure also.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Dental Pain!!!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-14-dental-pain/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-14T13:03:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-14T13:03:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-14:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-14-dental-pain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/14022011155-732859.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/14022011155-732859.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just what is the evolutionary advantage to having pain receptors in your teeth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I survived the weekend. But it wasn't easy, or something I'd like to do again. I was sitting at the door to the dentists this morning before 8am waiting to see if I could get for an …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/14022011155-732859.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/14022011155-732859.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just what is the evolutionary advantage to having pain receptors in your teeth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I survived the weekend. But it wasn't easy, or something I'd like to do again. I was sitting at the door to the dentists this morning before 8am waiting to see if I could get for an apointment. I was contemplating using pliers myself. The pain was agonyising. No matter how much I told myself pain isn't real, breath, think of something else - it didn't work. Drugs helped I think, but not enough. What did people do before Dentists and pain medication? (I suspect the pliers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget about worrying which tooth it was, I wanted them all out. Nothing so drastic yet, the suspect from last week did have a crack in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the pain continues, but wether nerve death, drugs or plain exhaustion its a bit less than the weekends levels. I'm told that it continue to go down now and in a couple of days not hurt at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can't wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: 2013-09-30 18:20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author: Megan Lee Webb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you. Glad your liking the site.  I also wonder how we managed. I recall my first long cycle - around Tasmania, I didn't have any gadgets. Contact with anyone was send a postcard, or phone a public phone box with a bundle of coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Loaded Troll on the road in Sydney</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-16-loaded-troll-on-the-/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-16T18:11:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-16T18:11:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-16:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-16-loaded-troll-on-the-/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011156-721521.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011156-721521.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011157-722267.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011157-722267.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd been staying with friends. It was terribly nice of them, but  decided today, time to move on. Because of unresolved  tooth issues, and waiting for front wheel bearing replacement, I need to stay about Sydney for a bit.  Options on the tooth are extract it or root canal and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011156-721521.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011156-721521.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011157-722267.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16022011157-722267.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd been staying with friends. It was terribly nice of them, but  decided today, time to move on. Because of unresolved  tooth issues, and waiting for front wheel bearing replacement, I need to stay about Sydney for a bit.  Options on the tooth are extract it or root canal and crown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While thinking about that, did lots on the bike. A rear Tubus Cosmo rack can be mounted as a front rack. This is great as it has a platform and is light; about 700gms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made up a bracket to mount the light above the front rack load. Need to get the wheel back to see how good this works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some photos of the bike when I stopped in the park for a repack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surly isn't as rigid as the Yuba. First ride fully loaded was almost like a piece of noodle - cooked, not raw. But this turned out to be the load not firmly fastened. With everything tied down good, it still has some flex, but handles fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to sort out somewhere to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Getting a good nights sleep</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-17-getting-a-good-night/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-17T08:24:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-17T08:24:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-17:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-17-getting-a-good-night/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17022011161-712720.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17022011161-712720.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the view from my breakfast spot. No, its not where I slept. Though I'll need to find a new spot for tonight. Got woken up about midnight by the security guards wanting to see identification and know what I was doing. I thought that was obvious -  sleeping! Reckon …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17022011161-712720.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17022011161-712720.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the view from my breakfast spot. No, its not where I slept. Though I'll need to find a new spot for tonight. Got woken up about midnight by the security guards wanting to see identification and know what I was doing. I thought that was obvious -  sleeping! Reckon I might not get away with it there again tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the midnight wake up, a good nights sleep was had. Even found a spot to charge my phone. Now if they just had free wifi it would be almost perfect. (Perfect would be no security guards waking you up, and free wifi.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worryingly, the tooth is hurting more than yesterday.  I'm wondering if this is just all the pain killers draining out of my system. Still on antibiotics, another few days left of that course. Will see how the pain develops today if at all, and go see the regular dentist again for an appointment to pull it out. Well, still wavering on root canal or pull out. More leaning to pull it out. Both have consequences and risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still feels like too much gear on the bike, even though I ditched stuff and got lighter stuff. Though, putting the tent on the back rack with the panniers and water isn't as bad as I thought for front wheel lift. Thinking about a basket on the platform on the front rack. Would be a handy place to drop the shopping, and commonly used items for the day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Escape the City!</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-20-escape-the-city/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-20T19:12:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-20T19:12:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-20:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-20-escape-the-city/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011162-790858.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011162-790858.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011163-792140.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011163-792140.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011164-792708.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011164-792708.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011165-793407.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011165-793407.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011166-794146.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011166-794146.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011167-794947.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011167-794947.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city just seemed too crowded. The press of people too much. So after being frozen in indecision on Thursday morning, I packed up and headed out of town that afternoon. Been camping in the bush for the three nights and will do a few more before  moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011162-790858.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011162-790858.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011163-792140.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011163-792140.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011164-792708.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011164-792708.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011165-793407.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011165-793407.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011166-794146.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011166-794146.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011167-794947.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/20022011167-794947.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city just seemed too crowded. The press of people too much. So after being frozen in indecision on Thursday morning, I packed up and headed out of town that afternoon. Been camping in the bush for the three nights and will do a few more before  moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is my tent in the bush with me in it:)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bike has been going good. I found that I needed to put the tent at least on the front rack to give some weight to the front climbing hills. Other wise all is as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the Troll: I'm running 165mm road cranks, because I like the shorter strokes. It also improves pedal ground clearance that little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back has a Rohloff hub, laced to Rigina (spelling) rims with black spokes. I'd probably to for silver spokes next time. They seemed to be thicker and don't rust. The hub gear gives easy positive changing all the time. I know you can change under load, but I tend to ease up and then change. I like the neat chain line, the low maintanence, no derailer hanging down and solid build of the wheel. Solid build because there is no dish needed. Also the cogs can both be turned around doubling their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tires are 26x2.00 Schwelbe Marathon Tour Plus, wraped up in Planet Bike Zefal mud guards. These guards are old and I haven't seen them in the shop in a long time. I think they are the best, as the clips that hold the guards in place can disengage easily. This is useful on the front wheel on bush tracks when a branch gets caught in the spokes. The clips pop open allowing the wheel to turn. The branch usually clears the forks, but certainly the mudguard doesn't scrunch up into the fork. A few minutes restores it all to as good as new.  There is heaps of clearance at the front fork for fatter tires. The rear is another story. I could go to larger tires if I put the wheel further back in the rear dropouts. Since I'm running 2.00 tires, and have the wheel almost all the way forward, there isn't a huge amount of space left. About 2.5 cm more and the tire would hit the rear stay brace behind the seat. The is a bit more clearance at the bottom chain stay brace.  The Tubus Cosmo rack has heaps of clearance, and isn't the limiting factor for tire size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can get measurements if people want of the spaces. I know that there is some info on the web on the Surly site about how large a tire can be placed. I think its 2.75 if you  have the wheel right back in the dropouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm presently running Shimano hydraulic disk brakes, but might change them to mechanical disks sometime. Since I want a front rack with a platform, the hoses from the brakes exit the levers at a bad angle, and want to project forward. A change of levers would fix this. But also the rear brake caliper bleed point is right were my foot will knock the cap of all the time. Previously I made a cover to stop this.  My hoses on the brakes are too long still and I'm not sure I'm going to get a nice neat line of the hoses at the front. Sticking out as they do, they are a concern for snagging them. Least with mechanical brakes, I can easily fix up a new cable. I don't carry spare hose and brake fluid. Something to think more about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've used the Tubus Cosmo rack on the front also. I might cut the rack down a bit - where the platform bars slope upwards. When I had the spring to stop the front wheel flopping, the rack didn't hit the frame. The cable tie holding the spring broke, the wheel will flop around until the rack hits the frame. Either I make a better mount for the spring, or shorten the rack so it doesn't hit the frame.  The front wheel floping also stresses the hydraulic hoses and gear cables. I feel the gear cables will survive that better, where as I'm not feeling so good about the hydraulic hoses being twisted so much.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Sydney again</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/02/2011-02-24-sydney-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-24T06:56:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-02-24T06:56:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-02-24:/posts/2011/02/2011-02-24-sydney-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/22022011171-757537.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/22022011171-757537.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just missed the train and waited 2 hours for the next one. I was damp. It was cold and windy. I returned to Sydney hoping to collect my front wheel and be gone again. Alas, this was not to be. Still waiting. How long does changing bearings on a Schmitt …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/22022011171-757537.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/22022011171-757537.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just missed the train and waited 2 hours for the next one. I was damp. It was cold and windy. I returned to Sydney hoping to collect my front wheel and be gone again. Alas, this was not to be. Still waiting. How long does changing bearings on a Schmitt hub take?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had a day of shivering in the park. Weather is cool and showery. Not the weather to have a cold wash in, or dry clothes. I need to do both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ate some Fava beans. Probably not a good seller with the name they have on the tin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slept in the park last night in my tent. Was okay. Not as good as out of Sydney, but better than the bench with security guards at midnight Was up and packed up  by 5:30 to avoid the morning joggers and dog walkers.  A spot to return to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Schmitt returns</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/03/2011-03-01-schmitt-returns/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-01T12:05:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-03-01T12:05:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-03-01:/posts/2011/03/2011-03-01-schmitt-returns/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/01032011172-749272.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/01032011172-749272.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally my wheel is back. The bearings were good, the problem was rust- a component inside. The hub is sealed, with a vent hole inside the axle. So never grease the quick release skewer as the grease can clog the breather hole. Since i use Pitlock skewers, i've never greased …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/01032011172-749272.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/01032011172-749272.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally my wheel is back. The bearings were good, the problem was rust- a component inside. The hub is sealed, with a vent hole inside the axle. So never grease the quick release skewer as the grease can clog the breather hole. Since i use Pitlock skewers, i've never greased them. I've also never had the hub underwater. So not sure why it was rusty. We'll have to see if it happens again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is good to have lights again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broke another rear spoke. Had the wheel checked for tension and trueness. Hope thats the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heart stop moment, i dropped the Pitlock key down a manhole. Yikes!!! This was in Newtown. Luckily i was able to lift tin cover up. Down i jumped and retrieved it. I also put the cover back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got asked for ID by the security guards again. Picked the wrong moment to move about. Still, least i was awake then.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Indecision (again)</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/03/2011-03-02-indecision-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-02T08:54:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-03-02T08:54:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-03-02:/posts/2011/03/2011-03-02-indecision-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tooth is still in my mouth. Dentist discussed the pros and cons of pulling it out verses root canal. So thee end of the appointment came without anything happening. Well, except talking. So, tooth is still there, root canal appointments booked for all of March. And I've still got another …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tooth is still in my mouth. Dentist discussed the pros and cons of pulling it out verses root canal. So thee end of the appointment came without anything happening. Well, except talking. So, tooth is still there, root canal appointments booked for all of March. And I've still got another week to be certain to pull it out. Arrrgghhh.. Choices. Choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros for pulling it out: cheap,  its done, can move on and deal with any problems later, other teeth could move affecting bite, more stress on other teeth, risk of damage to sinus, visible when smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons for root canal: 70% still fail. Expensive. Need crown which is also expensive. Worry about infection not being visible on x-rays, pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One argument says risk the root canal and it can always be pulled out later. This morning, I'm back to thinking pull it out,, get it over with and lets move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordered some panniers from Wiggle in UK last Friday. Same time I ordered some other items from a Sydney based internet only shop. The UK gear has arrived. Yes. It was processed, shipped, and delivered in 5 days.  The Sydney based gear has  as far as I can tell, not even left the warehouse. Dispite email saying when it was expected to ship and that further email would arrive if there was any problems, I've got nothing yet.  Any wonder why we order gear online from overseas?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Tooth no more</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/03/2011-03-08-tooth-no-more/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-08T10:30:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-03-08T10:30:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-03-08:/posts/2011/03/2011-03-08-tooth-no-more/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08032011175-753111.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08032011175-753111.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done. Its out. So far, relatively painless. But I should wait until the anaesthetic has worn off to say that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a flap of bone on the side of the jaw that is fractured that may need to come out. We're hoping that is will heal though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08032011175-753111.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/08032011175-753111.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done. Its out. So far, relatively painless. But I should wait until the anaesthetic has worn off to say that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a flap of bone on the side of the jaw that is fractured that may need to come out. We're hoping that is will heal though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now to rest up and wait for the bleeding to stop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>On the road again: Broke</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/03/2011-03-16-on-the-road-again-br/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-16T14:16:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-03-16T14:16:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-03-16:/posts/2011/03/2011-03-16-on-the-road-again-br/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16032011195-736395.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16032011195-736395.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I'm travelling again. The tooth seems to have healed. It is a bit sore still, but I'm hoping that it will not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed with some friends for a week, then left on my usual route. This time was different though - I didn't travel as far …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16032011195-736395.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/16032011195-736395.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I'm travelling again. The tooth seems to have healed. It is a bit sore still, but I'm hoping that it will not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed with some friends for a week, then left on my usual route. This time was different though - I didn't travel as far as I usually do. Maybe its the effects of the tooth extraction, too much eating, not enough exercise, an immune system upgrade thats underway (I've a cold). Probably its all of them. First day was 30km. Second day was 30km. And  was that a struggle. An hour after starting I was in survival mode: don't think, just pedal, or walk. Only thinking was to pick the next tree/rock/hill to get to.  I didn't go anywhere yesterday. Just sat about a campsite and ate, rested and read books. It was so peaceful where I was, I almost turned around this morning and went back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all the weighing up, shaving grams off small items. I left my friends house way over loaded. 8 books was the start of it, "gifts" that I needed to delay sending, the "extra" food that I bought because it was soo cheap, (and I made the mistake of shopping when hungry!). Today was able to post the "gifts" off. 4kg gone. 7 books given away, And by considerable effort, Over 3kg of food eaten. (Well that was over the last 3 days)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Troll is feeling much lighter now. I'm still carrying a couple of spares that I could get rid of. My Shimano sandals - I've a new pair, but am still wearing the old pair I patched with a cable tie. I've also a spare pair of thongs - still wearing the old pair patched with a cable tie there also. Lets see how long the old ones last..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my gear should fit in the rear panniers. Having the front ones helps balance the weight about. It also means that any food buys, I have lots of space to carry them. Finding anyting in the bags is also easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm back in the town of Broke. Dennis doesn't live here any more, so I'm having a peaceful time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many pictures so far. Was stuggling too much, and then just didn't feel like taking any.  Here is one of my Troll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frame size is 16" by Surly's measurements. The Norco was an 18.5", but everyone measures differently.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Lake Liddell</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/03/2011-03-17-lake-liddell/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-17T16:31:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-03-17T16:31:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-03-17:/posts/2011/03/2011-03-17-lake-liddell/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17032011196-787664.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17032011196-787664.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My early start was not to be. 2 km and 'pong'. Another broken spoke.I went back to the tables at Broke and replaced it, then headed to Singleton to get more. Most annoying. I'm expecting at this point to break more:( Time i think to learn wheel building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17032011196-787664.jpg" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://meganleewebb.github.io/images/2011/17032011196-787664.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My early start was not to be. 2 km and 'pong'. Another broken spoke.I went back to the tables at Broke and replaced it, then headed to Singleton to get more. Most annoying. I'm expecting at this point to break more:( Time i think to learn wheel building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shop in Singleton didn't have spokes or disk pads. The next town with bike shops is Tamworth. I'll be there Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving Singleton was very hot and humid. Stopped at a servo to top up on water, and just as i'm leaving it starts pouring. A before lunch thunder storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road is mostly with a wide shoulder, but every so often one of the blue "watch for bicycles" signs appears. This is when the shoulder shrinks or vanishes. Bummer! Usually its not for long. Though i'm about 20km from Musselbrook and the shoulder isn't to wide now. Lots of traffic here now. Lots of trucks. But so far everyone has been good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some water entered my panniers:( I need to roll them more. Luckily the sun is out, and its blowing a gale. I should have everything dry by dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that the machinary that is working near by stops tonight, else it'll be earplugs to sleep.  Talking to a local, it has been running 3 days non stop, but it should finish today, but you never know. Lake Liddell supplies 3 power stations. The machinary is putting in new rail tracks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Timor</title><link href="https://meganleewebb.github.io/posts/2011/03/2011-03-24-timor/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-24T05:41:00+11:00</published><updated>2011-03-24T05:41:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Megan Lee Webb</name></author><id>tag:meganleewebb.github.io,2011-03-24:/posts/2011/03/2011-03-24-timor/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well the machines stopped about 5ish, but that was just to lul everyone into a false sense of security. I woke up about 2am - what is that noise! They had started up again. With no hope of sleep - I left. A big Hi to Phil, Frazer and Brian, who invited …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well the machines stopped about 5ish, but that was just to lul everyone into a false sense of security. I woke up about 2am - what is that noise! They had started up again. With no hope of sleep - I left. A big Hi to Phil, Frazer and Brian, who invited me to their camp. Phil is chasing fish - not any fish. Carp. These are the fish every other fisherman i've met curses and throws out. Phil is only after carp. He's looking for big ones only - up over 20kg would make him really happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road to Musselbrook is not that wide, but has some shoulder. Same for the road to Scone. Not much traffic as you can expect at 3am. A worrying bunch walking along the streets in Mussellbrook when I stopped at the lights. Had me worried for a bit until I could read the signs on their shirts - pest control. Shooting birds as night. I didn't ask what type the rifle was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrived in Scone at 5am. Quiet it was. Just the way I like towns. Coles opened at 6. Got some food and went to find a park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected I broke another spoke. This time I've loosened some of the other spokes. I've tried to get them all the same tension and have the wheel true. Last time the wheel was true, but some spokes felt tighter. Feeling a bit more confident this time. Hoping this is my last one. I'm almost out of spokes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn't feeling the best so hung out in the park trying to nap. But more road works. When the thumpers started, I new it was time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gundy was nice, but with a wedding on, it was going to be busy. Timor was only just down the road lets head there. The road got hilly. I was feeling tired. At 6 i arrived, found a spot and just about to sleep when a car stopped. I'd picked the tennis grounds. And it was tennis night. Didn't matter I fell asleep anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>